<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<!-- K-Mod hints -->
	<!-- Style guidelines (from CIV4GameText_Strategy.xml): -->
	<!-- Technologies should be colored COLOR_TECH_TEXT (example: [COLOR_TECH_TEXT]Bronze Working[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Unit should be colored COLOR_UNIT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_UNIT_TEXT]Archers[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Buildings should be colored COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT (example: [COLOR_BUILDING_TEXT]Theatre[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Projects should be colored COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_PROJECT_TEXT]SS Engine[COLOR_REVERT]) -->
	<!-- Anything else official (that should be capitalized) should be colored COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT (example: [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Trade Mission[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT] or [COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]Islam[COLOR_HIGHLIGHT_TEXT]) -->
<Civ4GameText xmlns="http://www.firaxis.com">	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SCYTHED_CHARIOT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The scythed chariot was a modified war chariot. The blades extended horizontally for about 1 meter (3 ft) to each side of the wheels. The Greek general Xenophon (430?354 BC), an eyewitness at the battle of Cunaxa, tells of them: "These had thin scythes extending at an angle from the axles and also under the driver's seat, turned toward the ground". Serrated bronze blades for chariot wheels have also been excavated from Chou-era pre-imperial Chinese sites.[PARAGRAPH:1]The scythed chariot was pulled by a team of four horses and manned by a crew of up to three men, one driver and two warriors. Theoretically the scythed chariot would plow through infantry lines, cutting combatants in half or at least opening gaps in the line which could be exploited.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_STOCK_EXCHANGE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A stock exchange or bourse is an exchange where stock brokers and traders can buy and/or sell stocks (also called shares), bonds, and other securities. Stock exchanges may also provide facilities for issue and redemption of securities and other financial instruments, and capital events including the payment of income and dividends. Securities traded on a stock exchange include stock issued by listed companies, unit trusts, derivatives, pooled investment products and bonds.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GARDEN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A garden is a planned space, usually outdoors, set aside for the display, cultivation, and enjoyment of plants and other forms of nature. The garden can incorporate both natural and man-made materials. The most common form today is known as a residential garden, but the term garden has traditionally been a more general one. Zoos, which display wild animals in simulated natural habitats, were formerly called zoological gardens. Western gardens are almost universally based on plants, with garden often signifying a shortened form of botanical garden.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HOOVER_DAM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Hoover Dam, once known as Boulder Dam, is a concrete arch-gravity dam in the Black Canyon of the Colorado River, on the border between the U.S. states of Nevada and Arizona. It was constructed between 1931 and 1936 during the Great Depression. Its construction was the result of a massive effort involving thousands of workers, and cost over one hundred lives. The dam was controversially named after President Herbert Hoover.[PARAGRAPH:1]A total of 3,250,000 cubic yards (2,480,000 cubic metre) of concrete was used in the dam before concrete pouring ceased on May 29, 1935. In addition, 1,110,000 cu yd (850,000 cubic metre) were used in the power plant and other works. More than 582 miles (937 km) of cooling pipes were placed within the concrete. Overall, there is enough concrete in the dam to pave a two-lane highway from San Francisco to New York. The annual generation of Hoover Dam varies. The maximum net generation was 10.348 TWh in 1984, and the minimum since 1940 was 2.648 TWh in 1956. The average has been about 4.2 TWh/year.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_CORPORATIONS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Corporations[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Founding a Corporation[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]There are a number of requirements that must be fulfilled before a player can found a Corporation. First they must have researched the Corporations Technology (except for the Silk Road), in addition to another more specific technology required by each Corporation. This second technology varies by Corporation. Once players have researched the proper techs, they must then move a Great Person into a city that has one or more of the resources in city proximity required by the Corporation they wish to create. By expending the proper type of Great Person, they may found the Corporate Headquarters in their city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spreading a Corporation[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Once a Corporation is constructed in a city, that city may produce Corporate Executives. The emissaries of economy and the missionaries of moolah, Corporate Executives spread Corporate presence outside the Headquarters city. By building a Corporate Executive and moving it to a city with the appropriate resources, a player may expand the influence of a Corporation and increase the income produced by his Corporate HQ.[PARAGRAPH:1]Two corporations that consume the same resource cannot coexist in the same city and it will cost extra to replace one Corporation that consumes a resource with another that consumes the same resource.[PARAGRAPH:1]You may block foreign Corporations from entering your cities by adopting the Central Planning civic.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_1_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Silk Road or Silk Route was an ancient network of trade routes that were central to cultural interaction through regions of the Asian continent connecting the West and East from China to the Mediterranean Sea. [NEWLINE][TAB]The Silk Road derives its name from the lucrative trade in Chinese silk carried out along its length, beginning during the Han dynasty (207 BCE - 220 CE). The Central Asian sections of the trade routes were expanded around 114 BCE by the Han dynasty, largely through the missions and explorations of the Chinese imperial envoy, Zhang Qian. The Chinese took great interest in the safety of their trade products and extended the Great Wall of China to ensure the protection of the trade route.[PARAGRAPH:1]Trade on the Silk Road was a significant factor in the development of the civilizations of China, the Indian subcontinent, Persia, Europe, the Horn of Africa and Arabia, opening long-distance, political and economic relations between the civilizations. Though silk was certainly the major trade item from China, many other goods were traded, and religions, syncretic philosophies, and various technologies, as well as diseases, also travelled along the Silk Routes. In addition to economic trade, the Silk Road served as a means of carrying out cultural trade among the civilizations along its network.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_2_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The United East Indian Company was originally established as a chartered company in 1602, when the Dutch government granted it a 21-year monopoly on Dutch spice trade. It is often considered to have been the first multinational corporation in the world and it was the first company to issue stock. It was a powerful company, possessing quasi-governmental powers, including the ability to wage war, imprison and execute convicts, negotiate treaties, strike its own coins, and establish colonies. Statistically, the VOC eclipsed all of its rivals in the Asia trade. Between 1602 and 1796 the VOC sent almost a million Europeans to work in the Asia trade on 4,785 ships, and netted for their efforts more than 2.5 million tons of Asian trade goods. By contrast, the rest of Europe combined sent only 882,412 people from 1500 to 1795, and the fleet of the English (later British) East India Company, the VOC's nearest competitor, was a distant second to its total traffic with 2,690 ships and a mere one-fifth the tonnage of goods carried by the VOC. The VOC enjoyed huge profits from its spice monopoly through most of the 17th century.[PARAGRAPH:1]Having been set up in 1602, to profit from the Malukan spice trade, in 1619 the VOC established a capital in the port city of Jayakarta and changed the city name into Batavia (now Jakarta). Over the next two centuries the Company acquired additional ports as trading bases and safeguarded their interests by taking over surrounding territory. It remained an important trading concern and paid an 18% annual dividend for almost 200 years. Weighed down by corruption in the late 18th century, the Company went bankrupt and was formally dissolved in 1800, its possessions and the debt being taken over by the government of the Dutch Batavian Republic. The VOC's territories became the Dutch East Indies and were expanded over the course of the 19th century to include the whole of the Indonesian archipelago, and in the 20th century would form the Republic of Indonesia.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_3_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Originally known as the Company of Royal Adventurers Trading to Africa, by its charter issued in 1660 it was granted a monopoly over English trade with West Africa. With the help of the army and navy, it established forts on the West African coast that served as staging and trading stations and was responsible for seizing any English ships that attempted to operate in violation of the company's monopoly. In the prize court, the King received half of the proceeds and the company half.[NEWLINE][TAB]The company fell heavily into debt in 1667, during the war with the Netherlands, the very war it had itself started when its Admiral Robert Holmes had attacked the Dutch African trade posts in 1664, as it had lost most of its forts on the African coast except for Cape Corse. For several years after that, the company maintained some desultory trade, including licensing single-trip private traders, but its biggest effort was the creation in 1668 of the Gambia Adventurers, a new company separately subscribed and granted a ten-year license for African trade north of the Bight of Benin with effect from 1 January 1669. In 1672, the original Company re-emerged, re-structured and with a new charter from the king, as the new Royal African Company. Its new charter was broader than the old one and included the right to set up forts and factories, maintain troops and exercise martial law in West Africa, in pursuit of trade in gold, silver and slaves. At the end of 1678, the license to the Gambia Adventurers expired and its Gambian trade was merged into the company.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_4_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In economics, a luxury good is a good for which demand increases more than proportionally as income rises, and is a contrast to a "necessity good", for which demand increases proportionally less than income. Luxury goods are often synonymous with superior goods and veblen goods. Though often verging on the meaningless in modern marketing, "luxury" remains a legitimate and current technical term in art history for objects that are especially highly decorated to very high standards and use expensive materials. The term is especially used for medieval manuscripts to distinguish between practical working books for normal use, and fully illuminated manuscripts, that were often bound in treasure bindings with metalwork and jewels. These are often much larger, with less text on each page and many illustrations, and if liturgical texts were originally usually kept on the altar or sacristy rather any library that the church or monastery who owned them may have had. Secular luxury manuscripts were commissioned by the very wealthy and differed in the same ways from cheaper books. "Luxury" may be used for other applied arts where both utilitarian and luxury versions of the same types of objects were made. This might cover metalwork, ceramics, glass, arms and armour, and a wide range of objects. It is much less used for objects with no function beyond being an artwork: paintings, drawings and sculpture, even though the disparity in cost between an expensive and cheap work may have been as large.[PARAGRAPH:1]Luxury goods are said to have high income elasticity of demand: as people become wealthier, they will buy more and more of the luxury good. This also means, however, that should there be a decline in income its demand will drop. Income elasticity of demand is not constant with respect to income, and may change sign at different levels of income. That is to say, a luxury good may become a normal good or even an inferior good at different income levels, e.g. a wealthy person stops buying increasing numbers of luxury cars for his automobile collection to start collecting airplanes (at such an income level, the luxury car would become an inferior good). Some luxury products have been claimed to be examples of Veblen goods, with a positive price elasticity of demand: for example, making a perfume more expensive can increase its perceived value as a luxury good to such an extent that sales can go up, rather than down.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_5_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The four key drivers of the Industrial Revolution were textile manufacturing, iron founding, steam power and cheap labour. Before the 18th century, the manufacture of cloth was performed by individual workers, in the premises in which they lived and goods were transported around the country by packhorses or by river navigations and contour-following canals that had been constructed in the early 18th century. In the mid-18th century, artisans were inventing ways to become more productive. Silk, wool, and fustian fabrics were being eclipsed by cotton which became the most important textile. Innovations in carding and spinning enabled by advances in cast iron technology resulted in the creation of larger spinning mules and water frames. The machinery was housed in water-powered mills on streams. The need for more power stimulated the production of steam-powered beam engines, and rotative mill engines transmitting the power to line shafts on each floor of the mill. Surplus power capacity encouraged the construction of more sophisticated power looms working in weaving sheds. The scale of production in the mill towns round Manchester created a need for a commercial structure; for a cotton exchange and warehousing. The technology was used in woollen and worsted mills in the West Riding of Yorkshire and elsewhere.[NEWLINE][TAB]With the Cartwright Loom, the Spinning Mule and the Boulton and Watt steam engine, the pieces were in place to build a mechanised textile industry. From this point there were no new inventions, but a continuous improvement in technology as the mill-owner strove to reduce cost and improve quality. Developments in the transport infrastructure - the canals and, after 1831, the railways - facilitated the import of raw materials and export of finished cloth.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_6_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The fishing industry includes any industry or activity concerned with taking, culturing, processing, preserving, storing, transporting, marketing or selling fish or fish products. It is defined by the Food and Agriculture Organization as including recreational, subsistence and commercial fishing, and the harvesting, processing, and marketing sectors. The commercial activity is aimed at the delivery of fish and other seafood products for human consumption or as input factors in other industrial processes. Directly or indirectly, the livelihood of over 500 million people in developing countries depends on fisheries and aquaculture. [NEWLINE][TAB]Commercial fishing is the activity of catching fish and other seafood for commercial profit, mostly from wild fisheries. It provides a large quantity of food to many countries around the earth, but those who practice it as an industry must often pursue fish far into the ocean under adverse conditions. Large-scale commercial fishing is also known as industrial fishing. This profession has gained in popularity with the development of shows such as Deadliest Catch, Swords, and Wicked Tuna. The major fishing industries are not only owned by major corporations but by small families as well. The industry has had to adapt through the years in order to keep earning a profit. Commercial fishermen harvest a wide variety of animals, ranging from tuna, cod, carp, and salmon to shrimp, krill, lobster, clams, squid, and crab, in various fisheries for these species. [PARAGRAPH:1]There are large and important fisheries worldwide for various species of fish, mollusks, crustaceans, and echinoderms. However, a very small number of species support the majority of the world's fisheries. Some of these species are herring, cod, anchovy, tuna, flounder, mullet, squid, shrimp, salmon, crab, lobster, oyster and scallops. All except these last four provided a worldwide catch of well over a million tonnes in 1999, with herring and sardines together providing a catch of over 22 million metric tons in 1999. Many other species are fished in smaller numbers.[NEWLINE][TAB]The industry, in 2006, also managed to generate over 185 billion dollars in sales and also provide over two million jobs in the United States, according to an economic report released by NOAA's Fisheries Service. Commercial fishing may offer an abundance of jobs, but the pay varies from boat to boat, season to season.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_7_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Before about 1860 steel was an expensive product, made in small quantities and used mostly for swords, tools and cutlery; all large metal structures were made of wrought or cast iron. Steelmaking was centered in Sheffield, Britain, which supplied the European and the American markets. The introduction of cheap steel was due to the Bessemer and the open hearth processes, two technological advances made in England. In the Bessemer process, molten pig iron is converted to steel by blowing air through it after it was removed from the furnace. The air blast burned the carbon and silicon out of the pig iron, releasing heat and causing the temperature of the molten metal to rise. Henry Bessemer demonstrated the process in 1856 and had a successful operation going by 1864. By 1870 Bessemer steel was widely used for ship plate. By the 1850s, the speed, weight, and quantity of railway traffic was limited by the strength of the wrought iron rails in use. The solution was to turn to steel rails, which the Bessemer process made competitive in price. Experience quickly proved steel had much greater strength and durability and could handle the increasingly heavy and faster engines and cars. After 1890 the Bessemer process was gradually supplanted by open-hearth steelmaking and by the middle of the 20th century was no longer in use. The open-hearth process originated in the 1860s in Germany and France. The usual open-hearth process used pig iron, ore, and scrap, and became known as the Siemens-Martin process. Its process allowed closer control over the composition of the steel; also, a substantial quantity of scrap could be included in the charge. The crucible process remained important for making high-quality alloy steel into the 20th century. By 1900 the electric arc furnace was adapted to steelmaking and by the 1920s, the falling cost of electricity allowed it to largely supplant the crucible process for specialty steels.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_8_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Petroleum in an unrefined state has been utilized by humans for over 5000 years. Oil in general has been used since early human history to keep fires ablaze and in warfare. Its importance to the world economy evolved slowly, with whale oil used for lighting in the 19th century and wood and coal used for heating and cooking well into the 20th century. The Industrial Revolution generated an increasing need for energy which was met mainly by coal, and with other sources including whale oil. However, when it was discovered that kerosene could be extracted from crude oil and used as a lighting and heating fuel, petroleum was in great demand, and by the early twentieth century had become the most valuable commodity traded on world markets.[PARAGRAPH:1]The petroleum industry includes the global processes of exploration, extraction, refining, transporting (often by oil tankers and pipelines), and marketing petroleum products. The largest volume products of the industry are fuel oil and gasoline (petrol). Petroleum (oil) is also the raw material for many chemical products, including pharmaceuticals, solvents, fertilizers, pesticides, and plastics. The industry is usually divided into three major components: upstream, midstream and downstream. Midstream operations are usually included in the downstream category. Petroleum is vital to many industries, and is of importance to the maintenance of industrial civilization in its current configuration, and thus is a critical concern for many nations. Oil accounts for a large percentage of the world's energy consumption, ranging from a low of 32% for Europe and Asia, to a high of 53% for the Middle East.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_9_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Fast food, a type of mass-produced food that is prepared and served very quickly, was first popularized in the 1950s in the United States, and may be relatively less nutritionally valuable compared to other foods and dishes. While any meal with low preparation time can be considered fast food, typically the term refers to food sold in a restaurant or store with preheated or precooked ingredients, and served to the customer in a packaged form for take-out/take-away. Fast food restaurants are traditionally distinguished by their ability to serve food via a drive-through. The term "fast food" was recognized in a dictionary by Merriam-Webster in 1951. Outlets may be stands or kiosks, which may provide no shelter or seating, or fast food restaurants (also known as quick service restaurants). Franchise operations that are part of restaurant chains have standardized foodstuffs shipped to each restaurant from central locations.[PARAGRAPH:1]According to the National Institutes of Health (NIH), fast foods are quick and cheap alternatives to home-cooked meals. They are also high in saturated fat, sugar, salt and calories. Eating too much fast food has been linked to, among other things, obesity and high cholesterol.[NEWLINE][TAB]The traditional family dinner is increasingly being replaced by the consumption of takeaway, or eating "on the run". As a result, the time invested on food preparation is getting lower and lower, with an average couple in the United States spending 47 minutes and 19 minutes per day, carrying out food preparation.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_10_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The electronics industry, especially meaning consumer electronics, emerged in the 20th century and has now become a global industry worth billions of dollars. Contemporary society uses all manner of electronic devices built in automated or semi-automated factories operated by the industry. Products are assembled from integrated circuits, principally by photolithography of printed circuit boards. The size of the industry and the use of toxic materials, as well as the difficulty of recycling has led to a series of problems with electronic waste. International regulation and environmental legislation has been developed in an attempt to address the issues.[PARAGRAPH:1]The electric power industry began in the 19th century and this led to the development of all manner of inventions. Gramaphones were an early invention and this was followed by radio transmitters and receivers and televisions. The first digital computers were built in the 1940s with a slow development in technology and total sales. In the 1990s the personal computer became popular. A large part of the electronics industry is now involved with digital technology. The industry now employs large numbers of electronics engineers and electronics technicians to design, develop, test, manufacture, install, and repair electrical and electronic equipment such as communication equipment, medical monitoring devices, navigational equipment, and computers. Common parts manufactured are connectors, system components, cell systems, computer accessories, and these are made of alloy steel, copper, brass, stainless steel, plastic, steel tubing and other materials.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CORPORATION_11_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The arms industry, a global business, manufactures and sells weapons and military technology and equipment. It consists of commercial industry involved in research and development, engineering, production, and the servicing of military material, equipment, and facilities. Arms-producing companies, also referred to as defense contractors or as the military industry, produce arms mainly for the armed forces of states. Departments of government also operate in the arms industry, buying and selling weapons, munitions and other military items. Products include guns, ammunition, missiles, military aircraft, military vehicles, ships, electronic systems, and more. The arms industry also provides other logistical and operational support.[PARAGRAPH:1]Many industrialized countries have a domestic arms-industry to supply their own military forces. Some countries also have a substantial legal or illegal domestic trade in weapons for use by its citizens. Illegal trade in small arms occurs in many countries and regions affected by political instability. The Small Arms Survey estimates that 875 million small arms circulate worldwide, produced by more than 1,000 companies from nearly 100 countries. Contracts to supply a given country's military are awarded by governments, making arms contracts of substantial political importance. The link between politics and the arms trade can result in the development of what U.S. President Dwight D. Eisenhower described as a military-industrial complex, where the armed forces, commerce, and politics become closely linked, similarly to the European defence procurement. Various corporations, some publicly held, others private, bid for these contracts, which are often worth many billions of dollars. Sometimes, as with the contract for the international Joint Strike Fighter, a competitive tendering process takes place, with the decision made on the merits of the designs submitted by the companies involved. Other times, no bidding or competition takes place.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_MODERN_COMBAT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The use of blitzkrieg during the German invasion of France first demonstrated the power of speed and maneuverability over static artillery positions and trench defenses. Through the use of tanks, mechanized infantry, and close air support, the Germans were able to quickly break through linear defenses and capture the rear. The emphasis on maneuvering and speed to bypass enemy engagement remains a common strategy throughout the world, and collapsing an enemy's defenses by striking at deeper targets is-in a somewhat different way-a major strategy in fourth generation warfare. The contributions of the third generation were based on the concept of overcoming technological disadvantage through the use of clever strategy. As linear fighting came to an end, new ways of moving faster began to appear. The emphasis on cavalry moved from heavy armor to greater speed, the development of the helicopter allowed insertions in hostile territory, and advanced missile technology allowed forces to bypass enemy defenses and strike at targets from great distances. The speed inherent in these methods necessitated a greater degree of independence allowed to the units on the front lines. Greater trust needed to be placed in junior officers commanding sub-units by higher-ranking officers-a belief that they could adequately achieve their objectives without micromanagement from higher ranking commanders in command headquarters. Smaller units were allowed greater decision flexibility to deal with changing situations on the ground, rather than have decisions made for them by commanders who were distant from the front. This began to break down the regimented culture of order that was so important in previous theoretical eras of military command and control.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ALCHEMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Alchemy is a philosophical and protoscientific tradition practiced throughout Europe, Egypt and Asia. It aimed to purify, mature, and perfect certain objects. Common aims were chrysopoeia, the transmutation of "base metals" (e.g., lead) into "noble" ones (particularly gold); the creation of an elixir of immortality; the creation of panaceas able to cure any disease; and the development of an alkahest, a universal solvent. The perfection of the human body and soul was thought to permit or result from the alchemical magnum opus and, in the Hellenistic and western tradition, the achievement of gnosis. In Europe, the creation of a philosopher's stone was variously connected with all of these projects.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_ABSOLUTISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Absolute monarchy or despotic monarchy is a monarchical form of government in which the monarch has absolute power among his or her people. An absolute monarch wields unrestricted political power over the sovereign state and its people. Absolute monarchies are often hereditary but other means of transmission of power are attested. Absolute monarchy differs from constitutional monarchy, in which a monarch's authority in a constitutional monarchy is legally bounded or restricted by a constitution. In theory, the absolute monarch exercises total power over the land, yet in practice the monarchy is counterbalanced by political groups from among the social classes and castes of the realm, such as the aristocracy, clergy, and middle and lower classes.Some monarchies have weak or symbolic legislatures and other governmental bodies that the monarch can alter or dissolve at will. Countries where the monarch still maintains absolute power are Brunei, Qatar, Oman, Saudi Arabia, Swaziland, the emirates comprising the United Arab Emirates, and Vatican City.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_GUILDS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Guilds are associations of artisans or merchants who control the practice of their craft in a particular town. The earliest types of guild were formed as confraternities of tradesmen. They were organized in a manner something between a professional association, trade union, a cartel, and a secret society. They often depended on grants of letters patent by a monarch or other authority to enforce the flow of trade to their self-employed members, and to retain ownership of tools and the supply of materials. A lasting legacy of traditional guilds are the guildhalls constructed and used as meeting places.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_INDUSTRIALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Industrialisation or industrialization is the period of social and economic change that transforms a human group from an agrarian society into an industrial one, involving the extensive re-organisation of an economy for the purpose of manufacturing. As industrial workers' incomes rise, markets for consumer goods and services of all kinds tend to expand and provide a further stimulus to industrial investment and economic growth.[PARAGRAPH:1]The first transformation to an industrial economy from an agricultural one, known as the Industrial Revolution, took place from the mid-18th to early 19th century in certain areas in Europe and North America; starting in Great Britain, followed by Belgium, Germany, and France. Later commentators have called this the first industrial revolution. The "Second Industrial Revolution" labels the later changes that came about in the mid-19th century after the refinement of the steam engine, the invention of the internal combustion engine, the harnessing of electricity and the construction of canals, railways and electric-power lines. The invention of the assembly line gave this phase a boost. By the end of the 20th century, East Asia had become one of the most recently industrialised regions of the world.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_LEVY_ARMIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Levies are a political and economic system of Europe from the 9th to about the 15th century, based on the holding of all land in fief or fee and the resulting relation of lord to vassal and characterized by homage, legal and military service of tenants, and forfeiture. The legal and social system that evolved in W Europe in the 8th and 9th centuries, in which vassals were protected and maintained by their lords, usually through the granting of fiefs, and were required to serve under them in war.[PARAGRAPH:1]Under the feudal conditions for holding land in the medieval period, most peasants and freemen were liable to provide one man of suitable age per family for military duty when required by either the king or the local lord. The levies raised in this way fought as infantry under local superiors. Although the exact laws varied greatly depending on the country and the period, generally these levies were only obliged to fight for one to three months. Most were subsistence farmers, and it was in everyone's interest to send the men home for harvest-time.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MERCENARIES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A mercenary is a person who takes part in an armed conflict who is not a national or a party to the conflict and is "motivated to take part in the hostilities by the desire for private gain". In other words, a mercenary is a person who fights for personal gains of money or other recompense instead of fighting for the ideological interests of a country, whether they be for or against the existing government. In the last century, and as reflected in the Geneva Convention, mercenaries have increasingly come to be seen as less entitled to protections by rules of war than non-mercenaries. However, whether or not a person is a mercenary may be a matter of degree, as financial and national interests may overlap.[PARAGRAPH:1]An early recorded use of foreign auxiliaries dates back to Ancient Egypt, the thirteenth century BC, when Pharaoh Ramesses II used 11,000 mercenaries during his battles. A long established foreign corps in the Egyptian forces were the Medjay - a generic term given to tribal scouts and light infantry recruited from Nubia serving from the late period of the Old Kingdom through that of the New Kingdom. Other warriors recruited from outside the borders of Egypt included Libyan, Syrian and Canaanite contingents under the New Kingdom and Sherdens from Sardinia who appear in their distinctive horned helmets on wall paintings as body guards for Ramesses II. Celtic mercenaries were greatly employed in the Greek world (leading to the sack of Delphi and the Celtic settlement of Galatia). The Greek rulers of Ptolemaic Egypt, too, used Celtic mercenaries. Carthage was unique for relying primarily on mercenaries to fight its wars.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_MILITIA_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A militia generally is an army or other fighting unit that is composed of non-professional fighters, citizens of a nation or subjects of a state or government who can be called upon to enter a combat situation, as opposed to a professional force of regular, full-time military personnel, or historically, members of the warrior nobility class (e.g., knights or samurai). Unable to hold their own against properly trained and equipped professional forces, it is common for militias to engage in guerrilla warfare or defense instead of being used in open attacks and offensive actions.[PARAGRAPH:1]However, beginning as early as the late 20th century, some militias (particularly officially recognized and sanctioned militias of a government) act as professional forces, while still being "part-time" or "on-call" organizations. For instance, the members of some U.S. Army National Guard units are considered professional soldiers, as they are trained to maintain the same standards as their "full-time" (active duty) counterparts.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PANTHEON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A pantheon (literally "(a temple) of all gods") is the particular set of all gods of any polytheistic religion, mythology, or tradition:[PARAGRAPH:1]A pantheon is an overview of a given culture's gods and goddesses and reflects not only the society's values but also its sense of itself. A pantheon directed by a thunderboltwielding autocrat might suggest a patriarchy and the valuing of warrior skills. A pantheon headed by a great-mother goddess could suggest a village-based agricultural society. To confront the pantheon of the Egyptians is to confront a worldview marked by a sense of death and resurrection and the agricultural importance of the cycles of nature. The Greek pantheon is a metaphor for a pragmatic view of life that values art, beauty, and the power of the individual, and that is somewhat skeptical about human nature.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_STANDING_ARMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A standing army is a permanent, often professional, army. It is composed of full-time soldiers (who may be either career soldiers or conscripts) and is not disbanded during times of peace. It differs from army reserves, who are enrolled for the long term, but activated only during wars or natural disasters, and temporary armies, which are raised from the civilian population only during a war or threat of war and disbanded once the war or threat is over. Standing armies tend to be better equipped, better trained, and better prepared for emergencies, defensive deterrence, and particularly, wars. The term dates from approximately 1600, although the phenomenon it describes is much older.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_PUBLIC_WELFARE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Welfare is the provision of a minimal level of well-being and social support for all citizens, sometimes referred to as public aid. In most developed countries welfare is largely provided by the government, and to a lesser extent, charities, informal social groups, religious groups, and inter-governmental organizations. The welfare state expands on this concept to include services such as universal healthcare and unemployment insurance. Welfare can take a variety of forms, such as monetary payments, subsidies and vouchers, or housing assistance. Welfare systems differ from country to country, but welfare is commonly provided to individuals who are unemployed, those with illness or disability, the elderly, those with dependent children, and veterans. A person's eligibility for welfare may also be constrained by means testing or other conditions. Welfare is provided by governments or their agencies, by private organizations, or a combination of both. Funding for welfare usually comes from general government revenue, but when dealing with charities or NGOs, donations may be used. Some countries run conditional cash transfer welfare programs where payment is conditional on behaviour of the recipients.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_REPUBLIC_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A republic (from Latin: res publica) is a sovereign state or country which is organised with a form of government in which power resides in elected individuals representing the citizen body and government leaders exercise power according to the rule of law. In modern times, the definition of a republic is commonly limited to a government which excludes a monarch. Republics became more common in the Western world starting in the late 18th century, eventually displacing absolute monarchy as the most common form of government in Europe. In modern republics the executive is legitimized both by a constitution and by popular suffrage.[PARAGRAPH:1]In liberal democracies presidents are elected, either directly by the people or indirectly by a parliament or council. Typically in presidential and semi-presidential systems the president is directly elected by the people, or is indirectly elected as done in the United States. In that country the president is officially elected by an electoral college, chosen by the States, all of which do so by direct election of the electors. The indirect election of the president through the electoral college conforms to the concept of republic as one with a system of indirect election. In the opinion of some, direct election confers legitimacy upon the president and gives the office much of its political power. However, this concept of legitimacy differs from that expressed in the United States Constitution which established the legitimacy of the United States president as resulting from the signing of the Constitution by nine states. The idea that direct election is required for legitimacy also contradicts the spirit of the Great Compromise, whose actual result was manifest in the clause that provides voters in smaller states with slightly more representation in presidential selection than those in large states.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SCHOLASTICISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Scholasticism is a method of critical thought which dominated teaching by the academics ("scholastics," or "schoolmen") of medieval universities in Europe from about 1100 to 1700, and a program of employing that method in articulating and defending dogma in an increasingly pluralistic context. It originated as an outgrowth of, and a departure from, Christian monastic schools at the earliest European universities.[PARAGRAPH:1]Not so much a philosophy or a theology as a method of learning, scholasticism places a strong emphasis on dialectical reasoning to extend knowledge by inference, and to resolve contradictions. Scholastic thought is also known for rigorous conceptual analysis and the careful drawing of distinctions. In the classroom and in writing, it often takes the form of explicit disputation: a topic drawn from the tradition is broached in the form of a question, opponents' responses are given, a counterproposal is argued and opponent's arguments rebutted. Because of its emphasis on rigorous dialectical method, scholasticism was eventually applied to many other fields of study.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SECULARISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Secularism is the principle of the separation of government institutions and persons mandated to represent the state from religious institutions and religious dignitaries. One manifestation of secularism is asserting the right to be free from religious rule and teachings, or, in a state declared to be neutral on matters of belief, from the imposition by government of religion or religious practices upon its people. Another manifestation of secularism is the view that public activities and decisions, especially political ones, should be uninfluenced by religious beliefs and/or practices.[PARAGRAPH:1]The purposes and arguments in support of secularism vary widely. In European laicism, it has been argued that secularism is a movement toward modernization, and away from traditional religious values (also known as secularization). This type of secularism, on a social or philosophical level, has often occurred while maintaining an official state church or other state support of religion. In the United States, some argue that state secularism has served to a greater extent to protect religion and the religious from governmental interference, while secularism on a social level is less prevalent. Within countries as well, differing political movements support secularism for varying reasons.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SECULARISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Self-sufficiency (also called self-containment) is the state of not requiring any aid, support, or interaction, for survival; it is therefore a type of personal or collective autonomy. On a national scale, a totally self-sufficient economy that does not trade with the outside world is called an autarky. The term self-sufficiency is usually applied to varieties of sustainable living in which nothing is consumed outside of what is produced by the self-sufficient individuals.[PARAGRAPH:1]Practices that enable or aid self-sufficiency include autonomous building, permaculture, sustainable agriculture, and renewable energy. The term is also applied to limited forms of self-sufficiency, for example growing one's own food or becoming economically independent of state subsidies.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_FLOATING_GARDENS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Floating Garden is a method of ancient Mesoamerican agriculture which used small, rectangle-shaped areas of fertile arable land to grow crops on the shallow lake beds in the Valley of Mexico.  Often referred to as "floating gardens," Floating Gardens were artificial islands that usually measured roughly 30 × 2.5 m (98 × 8.2 ft), although they were sometimes longer. They were created by staking out the shallow lake bed and then fencing in the rectangle with wattle. The fenced-off area was then layered with mud, lake sediment, and decaying vegetation, eventually bringing it above the level of the lake. Often trees were planted at the corners to secure the Floating Garden. Floating Gardens were separated by channels wide enough for a canoe to pass.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_RED_FORT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Red Fort, or Lal Qila, is a 17th century fort complex constructed by the Mughal emperor Shah Jahan in the walled city of Old Delhi (in present day Delhi, India). Shah Jahan moved his capital here from Agra in a move designed to bring prestige to his reign, and to provide ample opportunity to apply his ambitious building schemes and interests. It served as the capital of the Mughals until 1857, when Mughal emperor Bahadur Shah Zafar was exiled by the British Indian  government. [PARAGRAPH:1]Shah Jahan started construction of the massive fort in 1638 and work was completed in 1648. The Red Fort was originally referred to as "Qila-i-Mubarak" (the blessed fort), because it was the residence of the royal family. The layout of the Red Fort was organised to retain and integrate this site with the Salimgarh Fort. The fortress palace was an important focal point of the medieval city of Shahjahanabad. The planning and aesthetics of the Red Fort represent the zenith of Mughal creativity which prevailed during the reign of Emperor Shah Jahan.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HARMANDIR_SAHIB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Harmandir Sahib, also referred to as the Golden Temple, is a prominent Sikh Gurdwara located in the city of Amritsar, Punjab, India. Construction of the Gurdwara was begun by Guru Ram Das ji, the fourth Sikh Guru, and completed by his successor, Guru Arjan Dev ji. In 1604, Guru Arjan Dev ji completed the Adi Granth, the holy scripture of Sikhism, and installed it in the Gurdwara. In 1634, Guru Hargobind left Amritsar for the Shivalik Hills and for the remainder of the seventeenth century the city and Gurdwara was in the hands of forces hostile to the Sikh Gurus. During the eighteenth century, Sri Harmandir Sahib was the site of frequent fighting between the Sikhs on one side and either Mughal or Afghan forces on the other side and the Gurdwara occasionally suffered damage. In the early nineteenth century, Maharaja Ranjit Singh secured the Punjab region from outside attack and covered the upper floors of the Gurdwara with gold, which gives it its distinctive appearance and English name of "Golden Temple".[PARAGRAPH:1]The present day Golden Temple was rebuilt in 1764 by Maharaja Jassa Singh Ahluwalia (1718-1783) with the help of other Misl Sikh chieftains.The gold plating of all the domes of Sri Darbar Sahib was done by Maharaja Jassa Singh Ahluwalia's descendents. Between 1802-1830 Ranjit Singh did the sewa of adding gold plating and marble to the Gurdwara, while the interior was decorated with fresco work and gemstones.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_WESTMINSTER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Palace of Westminster is the meeting place of the House of Commons and the House of Lords, the two houses of the Parliament of the United Kingdom. Commonly known as the Houses of Parliament after its tenants, the Palace lies on the Middlesex bank of the River Thames in the City of Westminster, in central London. Its name, which derives from the neighbouring Westminster Abbey, may refer to either of two structures: the Old Palace, a medieval building complex that was destroyed by fire in 1834, and its replacement New Palace that stands today. For ceremonial purposes, the palace retains its original style and status as a royal residence.[PARAGRAPH:1]The first royal palace was built on the site in the eleventh century, and Westminster was the primary London residence of the Kings of England until a fire destroyed much of the complex in 1512. After that, it served as the home of Parliament, which had been meeting there since the thirteenth century, and the seat of the Royal Courts of Justice, based in and around Westminster Hall. In 1834, an even greater fire ravaged the heavily rebuilt Houses of Parliament, and the only structures of significance to survive were Westminster Hall, the Cloisters of St Stephen's, the Chapel of St Mary Undercroft and the Jewel Tower.[PARAGRAPH:1]The subsequent competition for the reconstruction of the Palace was won by architect Charles Barry and his design for a building in the Perpendicular Gothic style. The remains of the Old Palace (with the exception of the detached Jewel Tower) were incorporated in its much larger replacement, which contains over 1,100 rooms organised symmetrically around two series of courtyards. Part of the New Palace's area of 3.24 hectares (8 acres) was reclaimed from the Thames, which is the setting of its principal façade, the 266-metre (873 ft) river front. Barry was assisted by Augustus W. N. Pugin, a leading authority on Gothic architecture and style, who provided designs for the decoration and furnishings of the Palace. Construction started in 1840 and lasted for thirty years, suffering great delays and cost overruns, as well as the death of both leading architects; works for the interior decoration continued intermittently well into the twentieth century. Major conservation work has been carried out since, due to the effects of London's air pollution, and extensive repairs took place after the Second World War, including the reconstruction of the Commons Chamber following its bombing in 1941.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Palace is one of the centres of political life in the United Kingdom; "Westminster" has become a metonym for the UK Parliament, and the Westminster system of government has taken its name after it. The Elizabeth Tower, in particular, which is often referred to by the name of its main bell, "Big Ben", is an iconic landmark of London and the United Kingdom in general, one of the most popular tourist attractions in the city and an emblem of parliamentary democracy. The Palace of Westminster has been a Grade I listed building since 1970 and part of a UNESCO World Heritage Site since 1987.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CERN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The European Organization for Nuclear Research (French: Organisation européenne pour la recherche nucléaire), known as CERN or Cern is an international organization whose purpose is to operate the world's largest particle physics laboratory, in the northwest suburbs of Geneva on the Franco-Swiss border. Established in 1954, the organization has 20 European member states.[PARAGRAPH:1]The term CERN is also used to refer to the laboratory, which employs just under 2,400 full-time employees, 1,500 part-time employees, and hosts some 10,000 visiting scientists and engineers, representing 608 universities and research facilities and 113 nationalities.[PARAGRAPH:1]CERN's main function is to provide the particle accelerators and other infrastructure needed for high-energy physics research. Numerous experiments have been constructed at CERN by international collaborations to make use of them. It is also the birthplace of the World Wide Web. The main site at Meyrin also has a large computer centre containing very powerful data-processing facilities primarily for experimental data analysis and, because of the need to make them available to researchers elsewhere, has historically been a major wide area networking hub.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_DRAFT_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Draft[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2]The [LINK=CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION]Conscription[\LINK] civic allows you to "draft" three units each turn. When you draft a unit in a city, some of the city's population is turned into a military unit.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Type[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]The drafted unit is the best "standard" foot-soldier available to your civilization: in early eras this might be a swordsman, while later it might be a maceman, musketeer or infantry.[PARAGRAPH:2][H2]Unit Experience[\H2][H2]Unhappiness[\H2][PARAGRAPH:2]Employing the draft causes [LINK=CONCEPT_HAPPINESS]Unhappiness[\LINK] in the city where you drafted the unit. This unhappiness isn't permanent: it dissipates over time. Drafting the same city multiple times will increase the unhappiness duration further.[PARAGRAPH:2]</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TERRACOTTA_ARMY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Terracotta Army is a collection of terracotta sculptures depicting the armies of Qin Shi Huang, the first Emperor of China. It is a form of funerary art buried with the emperor in 210-209 BC and whose purpose was to help guard his empire in his afterlife.[NEWLINE][TAB]The figures, dating from 3rd century BC, were discovered in 1974 by some local farmers in Lintong District, Xi'an, Shaanxi province, near the Mausoleum of the First Qin Emperor.[NEWLINE][TAB]The figures vary in height, according to their roles, with the tallest being the generals. The figures include warriors, chariots, horses, officials, acrobats, strongmen and musicians. Current estimates are that in the three pits containing the Terracotta Army there were over 8,000 soldiers, 130 chariots with 520 horses and 150 cavalry horses, the majority of which are still buried in the pits.[PARAGRAPH:2]The Terracotta Army was discovered in the spring of 1974 to the east of Xi'an in Shaanxi Province by a group of farmers when they were digging a water well 1.5 miles (2.4 km) north of Mount Li (Lishan), a region riddled with underground springs and watercourses. For centuries, there were reports of pieces of terracotta figures and fragments of the Qin necropolis - roofing tiles, bricks, and chunks of masonry - having been occasionally dug up in the area. This most recent discovery prompted archaeologists to investigate, and they unearthed the largest pottery figurine group ever found in China. In 195 B.C., Liu Bang - the first emperor of the dynasty that followed the Qin - had ordered that 'twenty households' should move to the site of the mausoleum of the First Emperor of Qin (Shi Huangdi, "Shi Huangdi" means the first emperor) to watch over the tomb. To this day, twenty villages sit in the immediate vicinity of the mausoleum, one of them the hamlet where those who made the discovery lived.[PARAGRAPH:2]In addition to the warriors, an entire man-made necropolis for the emperor has also been found. Qin Shi Huangdi's necropolis complex was constructed as a microcosm of his imperial palace or compound. It consists of several offices, halls, stables and other structures placed around the tomb mound which is surrounded by two solidly built rammed earth walls with gateway entrances. Up to 5 meters (16 feet) of reddish, sandy soil had accumulated over the site in the centuries following its construction, but archaeologists found evidence of earlier disturbances at the site. During the digs at Mount Li, archaeologists found several graves dating from the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, where diggers had apparently struck terracotta fragments which were then discarded as worthless back into the back-filled soil.[NEWLINE][TAB]According to historian Sima Qian (145-90 BC), work on this mausoleum began in 246 BC soon after Emperor Qin ascended the throne (then aged 13), and the full construction later involved 700,000 workers. Geographer Li Daoyuan, six centuries after the death of the First Emperor, recorded in Shui Jing Zhu that Mount Li was a favoured location due to its auspicious geology: "... famed for its jade mines, its northen side was rich in gold, and its southern side rich in beautiful jade; the First Emperor, envious of its fine reputation, therefore chose to be buried there". Sima Qian, in his most famous work, Shiji, completed a century after the mausoleum completion, wrote that the First Emperor was buried with palaces, towers, officials, valuable artefacts and wonderful objects. According to this account, there were 100 rivers simulated with flowing mercury, and above them the ceiling was decorated with heavenly bodies below which were the features of the land. Some translations of this passage refer to "models" or "imitations," those words however weren't used in the original text.[PARAGRAPH:2]Recent scientific work at the site has found high levels of mercury in the soil of the tomb mound, giving some credence to Sima Qian 's account of the emperor's tomb. The tomb mound is located at the foot of Mount Li as an earthen pyramid, and the tomb of Shi Huangdi appears to be a hermetically sealed space that is as big as a football pitch and located underneath the pyramid. The tomb remains unopened, one possible reason may be concerns about the preservation of valuable artifacts once the tomb is opened. For example, the painted surface of the terracotta army began to flake and fade once they have been excavated. Later historical accounts suggested that the tomb had been looted by Xiang Yu, a contender for the throne, five years after the death of the emperor, however there are indications that the tomb may not have been plundered.[NEWLINE][TAB]Only a portion of the site is presently excavated, and photos and video recordings are prohibited in some viewing areas. Only a few foreign dignitaries, such as Queen Elizabeth II, have been permitted to walk through the pits to observe the army at close quarters.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_HIMEJI_CASTLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Himeji Castle is a hilltop Japanese castle complex located in Himeji in Hyogo Prefecture. The castle is regarded as the finest surviving example of prototypical Japanese castle architecture, comprising a network of 83 buildings with advanced defensive systems from the feudal period. The castle is frequently known as Hakurojou or Shirasagijou ("White Heron Castle") because of its brilliant white exterior and supposed resemblance to a bird taking flight.[PARAGRAPH:2]Himeji Castle dates to 1333, when Akamatsu Norimura built a fort on top of Himeyama hill. The fort was dismantled and rebuilt as Himeyama Castle in 1346, and then remodeled into Himeji Castle two centuries later. Himeji Castle was then significantly remodeled in 1581 by Toyotomi Hideyoshi, who added a three-story castle keep. In 1600, Tokugawa Ieyasu awarded the castle to Ikeda Terumasa for his help in the Battle of Sekigahara, and Ikeda completely rebuilt the castle from 1601 to 1609, expanding it into a large castle complex. Several buildings were later added to the castle complex by Honda Tadamasa from 1617 to 1618. For over 400 years, Himeji Castle has remained intact, even throughout the extensive bombing of Himeji in World War II, and natural disasters such as the 1995 Great Hanshin earthquake.[NEWLINE][TAB]Himeji Castle is the largest and most visited castle in Japan, and it was registered in 1993 as one of the first UNESCO World Heritage Sites in the country. The area within the middle moat of the castle complex is a designated Special Historic Site and five structures of the castle are also designated National Treasures. Along with Matsumoto Castle and Kumamoto Castle, Himeji Castle is considered one of Japan's three premier castles. In order to preserve the castle buildings, it is currently undergoing restoration work that is expected to continue for several years.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRAFALGAR_SQUARE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Trafalgar Square is a public space and tourist attraction in central London, England, United Kingdom built around the area formerly known as Charing Cross. It is in the borough of the City of Westminster. At its centre is Nelson's Column, which is guarded by four lion statues at its base. There are a number of statues and sculptures in the square, with one plinth displaying changing pieces of contemporary art. The square is also used for political demonstrations and community gatherings, such as the celebration of New Year's Eve.[PARAGRAPH:1]The name commemorates the Battle of Trafalgar (1805), a British naval victory of the Napoleonic Wars over France. The original name was to have been "King William the Fourth's Square", but George Ledwell Taylor suggested the name "Trafalgar Square".[PARAGRAPH:1]In the 1820s, George IV engaged the architect John Nash to redevelop the area. Nash cleared the square as part of his Charing Cross Improvement Scheme. The present architecture of the square is due to Sir Charles Barry and was completed in 1845.[PARAGRAPH:1]Trafalgar Square is owned by the Queen in Right of the Crown, and managed by the Greater London Authority, while Westminster City Council owns the roads around the square, including the pedestrianised area of the North Terrace.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GUTENBERG_PRESS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>Johannes Gutenberg's work on the printing press began in approximately 1436 when he partnered with Andreas Dritzehn-a man who had previously instructed in gem-cutting-and Andreas Heilmann, owner of a paper mill. However, it was not until a 1439 lawsuit against Gutenberg that an official record existed; witnesses' testimony discussed Gutenberg's types, an inventory of metals (including lead), and his type molds. [PARAGRAPH:1]Having previously worked as a professional goldsmith, Gutenberg made skillful use of the knowledge of metals he had learned as a craftsman. He was the first to make type from an alloy of lead, tin, and antimony, which was critical for producing durable type that produced high-quality printed books and proved to be much better suited for printing than all other known materials. To create these lead types, Gutenberg used what is considered one of his most ingenious inventions, a special matrix enabling the quick and precise molding of new type blocks from a uniform template. His type case is estimated to have contained around 290 separate letter boxes, most of which were required for special characters, ligatures, punctuation marks, and so forth.[PARAGRAPH:1]Gutenberg is also credited with the introduction of an oil-based ink which was more durable than the previously used water-based inks. As printing material he used both paper and vellum (high-quality parchment). In the Gutenberg Bible, Gutenberg made a trial of coloured printing for a few of the page headings, present only in some copies. A later work, the Mainz Psalter of 1453, presumably designed by Gutenberg but published under the imprint of his successors Johann Fust and Peter Schöffer, had elaborate red and blue printed initials. The new era in print ushered in by the Internet is a distant mirror to Gutenberg's work which similarly revolutionized the printing process.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BONUS_BISON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Bison is a taxonomic group containing six species of large even-toed ungulates within the subfamily Bovinae. Two of these species still exist: the American plains bison (B. bison bison), and the American wood bison (B. bison athabascae) are subspecies found in North America and the European bison, or wisent (B. bonasus), found in Europe and the Caucasus.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_WARGALLEY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The ships of Medieval Europe were powered by sail or oar, or both. There were a large variety, mostly based in much older conservative design. Although wider and more frequent communications within Europe meant exposure to a variety of improvements, experimental failures were costly and rarely attempted. Ships in the north were influenced by Viking vessels, while those in the south by classical or Roman vessels. However, there was technological change. The different traditions used different construction methods; clinker in the north, carvel in the south. By the end of the period, carvel construction would come to dominate the building of large ships. The period would also see a shift from the steering oar or side rudder to the stern rudder and the development from single to multi-masted ships.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_VIKING_LONGSHIP_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Longships were a type of ship invented and used by the Norsemen for trade, commerce, exploration, and warfare during the Viking Age. A similar design was sailed by the Sumerians many centuries before.[citation needed] The longship's design evolved over many centuries, beginning in the Stone Age with the invention of the umiak and continuing up until the 6th century with clinker built ships like Nydam and Kvalsund. The longship appeared in its complete form between the 9th and 13th centuries. The character and appearance of these ships have been reflected in Scandinavian boat-building traditions until today. The particular skills and methods employed in making longships are still used worldwide, often with modern adaptations. They were all made out of wood, with cloth sails (woven wool) and had numerous details and carvings on the hull.[PARAGRAPH:1]The longships were characterized as a graceful, long, narrow and light wooden boat, with a shallow-draft hull designed for speed. The ship's shallow draft allowed navigation in waters only one metre deep and permitted random beach landings, while its light weight enabled it to be carried over portages or used bottoms up for shelter in camps. Longships were also double-ended, the symmetrical bow and stern letting the ship to reverse direction quickly without a turn around; this trait proved particularly useful at northern latitudes, where icebergs and sea ice posed hazards to navigation. Longships were fitted with oars along almost the entire length of the boat itself. Later versions had a rectangular sail on a single mast, which was used to replace or augment the effort of the rowers, particularly during long journeys. The average speed of Viking ships varied from ship to ship, but lay in the range of 5-10 knots (9.3-18.5 km/h) and the maximum speed of a longship under favorable conditions, was around 15 knots (28 km/h).[PARAGRAPH:1]Longships were the epitome of naval power in their time and were highly valued possessions. They were often communally owned by coastal farmers and commissioned by kings in times of conflict, in order to quickly assemble a large and powerful naval force. While longships were used by the Norse in warfare, they were mostly used for troop transports, not warships. In the tenth century, longships would sometimes be tied together in offshore battles to form a steady platform for infantry warfare. During the 9th century peak of the Viking expansion, large fleets set out to attack the degrading Frankish empire by attacking up navigable rivers such as the Seine. Rouen was sacked in 841, the year after the death of Louis the Pious, a son of Charlemagne. Quentovic, near modern Etables, was attacked in 842 and 600 Danish ships attacked Hamburg in 845. In the same year, 129 ships returned to attack up the Seine. They were called "dragonships" by enemies such as the English because they had a dragon-shaped bow. The Norse had a strong sense of naval architecture, and during the early medieval period they were advanced for their time.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HEAVY_FOOTMAN_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]It's a misconception that all of the Medieval Period was dominated by heavy cavalry, as this trend began only after the 10th Century. For centuries after the fall of the Western Roman Empire in 476 AD, heavy infantry was still favored in Western and Central European warfare, by the Franks, Visigoths, Anglo-Saxons and by the Arabs that invaded Spain. Only after the Carolingian Period and the rise of the Normans in the affairs of Western Europe we see a shifting trend in the course of warfare (i.e. Battle of Lechfeld, Battle of Hastings). With the proliferation and consolidation of the concept of chivalry, much focus was given to the knight as the central figure in warfare, nevertheless it's a false assumption that heavy infantry became obsolete during the period, as evidenced by the Scottish and Irish wars against the English, by the Flemish and Italian citizen-militias, and by the Byzantine methods of war (which was based on the Roman legionary and Greek hoplite models, see Skoutatoi). While the trend in Eastern Europe beyond the Dnieper among the nomadic peoples like the Pechenegs and Kypchaks was essentially based on horse archers, the peoples of modern Ukraine and western Russia favored a mix of heavy infantry and Asian-style cavalry warfare. Peoples like the Hungarians, Poles and Bulgarians gradually abandoned their native ways of warfare in favor of imitating the Western European knights or Byzantine heavy cavalry.[PARAGRAPH:1]All of this would change with the introduction of gunpowder in Europe in the late 14th century, and the highly successful and innovating pikemen tactics pioneered by the Swiss mercenaries led to the increased preference for mostly infantry professional armies. Gunpowder and the skillful use of the pike would give birth to the Middle Age heavy infantry and place it on an equal footing with cavalry. Heavy infantry would usually be armored like a knight with mail armor and an iron helmet, and would carry a pike. Other heavy infantry would probably be armed with little armor and a gunpowder weapon, which were capable of penetrating armor. The introduction of such weapons as gunpowder and the pike resulted in the reintroduction of the infantry into armies and shifted dominance of the battlefield away from the knights.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MASON_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Stonemasonry is one of the earliest trades in civilization's history. During the time of the Neolithic Revolution and domestication of animals, people learned how to use fire to create quicklime, plasters, and mortars. They used these to fashion homes for themselves with mud, straw, or stone, and masonry was born. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Ancients heavily relied on the stonemason to build the most impressive and long lasting monuments to their civilizations. The Egyptians built their pyramids, the civilizations of Central America had their step pyramids, the Persians their palaces, the Greeks their temples, and the Romans their public works and wonders. Among the famous ancient stonemasons is Sophroniscus, the father of Socrates, who was a stone-cutter. [PARAGRAPH:1]Castle building was an entire industry for the medieval stonemasons. When the Western Roman Empire fell, building in dressed stone decreased in much of Western Europe, and there was a resulting increase in timber-based construction. Stone work experienced a resurgence in the 9th and 10th centuries in Europe, and by the 12th century religious fervour resulted in the construction of thousands of impressive churches and cathedrals in stone across Western Europe.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TANNERY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In ancient history, tanning was considered a noxious or "odoriferous trade" and relegated to the outskirts of town, amongst the poor. Indeed, tanning by ancient methods is so foul smelling, tanneries are still isolated from those towns today where the old methods are used. Ancient civilizations used leather for waterskins, bags, harnesses and tack, boats, armour, quivers, scabbards, boots, and sandals. Tanning was being carried out by the South Asian inhabitants of Mehrgarh between 7000 and 3300 BC. Around 2500 BC, the Sumerians began using leather, affixed by copper studs, on chariot wheels.[PARAGRAPH:1]Skins typically arrived at the tannery dried stiff and dirty with soil and gore. First, the ancient tanners would soak the skins in water to clean and soften them. Then they would pound and scour the skin to remove any remaining flesh and fat. Next, the tanner needed to remove the hair from the skin. This was done by either soaking the skin in urine[citation needed], painting it with an alkaline lime mixture, or simply allowing the skin to putrefy for several months then dipping it in a salt solution. After the hairs were loosened, the tanners scraped them off with a knife.[PARAGRAPH:1]Once the hair was removed, the tanners would "bate" (soften) the material by pounding dung into the skin, or soaking the skin in a solution of animal brains. Bating was a fermentative process which relied on enzymes produced by bacteria found in the dung. Among the kinds of dung commonly used were those of dogs or pigeons. Sometimes, the dung was mixed with water in a large vat, and the prepared skins were kneaded in the dung water until they became supple from bacterial enzyme action, but not too soft. The ancient tanner might use his bare feet to knead the skins in the dung water, and the kneading could last two or three hours.[PARAGRAPH:1]This combination of urine, animal feces, and decaying flesh made ancient tanneries malodorous. Children employed as dung gatherers were a common sight in ancient cities. Also common were "piss-pots" located on street corners, where human urine could be collected for use in tanneries or by washerwomen. In some variations of the process, cedar oil, alum, or tannin were applied to the skin as a tanning agent. As the skin was stretched, it would lose moisture and absorb the agent.[PARAGRAPH:1]Leftover leather would be turned into glue. Tanners would place scraps of hides in a vat of water and let them deteriorate for months. The mixture would then be placed over a fire to boil off the water to produce glue.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MISSILE_SUBMARINE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A ballistic missile submarine is a submarine deploying submarine-launched ballistic missiles (SLBMs) with nuclear warheads. These submarines became a major weapon system in the Cold War because of their nuclear deterrence capability. They can fire missiles thousands of kilometers from their targets, and acoustic quieting makes them very difficult to detect, thus making them a survivable deterrent in the event of a first strike and a key element of the mutual assured destruction policy of nuclear deterrence.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CORVEE_SYSTEM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Corvée is a form of unpaid, unfree labor, which is intermittent in nature and for limited periods of time: typically only a certain number of days' work each year.[PARAGRAPH:1]Statute labour is a corvée imposed by a state for the purposes of public works. As such it represents a form of levy (taxation). Unlike other forms of levy, such as a tithe, a corvée does not require the population to have land, crops or cash. It was thus favored in historical economies in which barter was more common than cash transactions and/or circulating money is in short supply. The obligation for tenant farmers to perform corvée work for landlords on private landed estates has been widespread throughout history. The term is most typically used in reference to medieval and early modern Europe, where work was often expected by a feudal landowner (of their vassals), or by a monarch of their subjects.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ABSOLUTISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Absolute monarchy or despotic monarchy is a monarchical form of government in which the monarch has absolute power among his or her people. An absolute monarch wields unrestricted political power over the sovereign state and its people. Absolute monarchies are often hereditary but other means of transmission of power are attested. Absolute monarchy differs from constitutional monarchy, in which a monarch's authority in a constitutional monarchy is legally bounded or restricted by a constitution.[PARAGRAPH:1]In theory, the absolute monarch exercises total power over the land, yet in practice the monarchy is counterbalanced by political groups from among the social classes and castes of the realm, such as the aristocracy, clergy, and middle and lower classes.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_AGRARIANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Agrarianism has two common meanings. The first meaning refers to a social philosophy or political philosophy which values rural society as superior to urban society, the independent farmer as superior to the paid worker, and sees farming as a way of life that can shape the ideal social values. It stresses the superiority of a simpler rural life as opposed to the complexity of city life, with its banks and factories.[PARAGRAPH:1]Secondly, the term "agrarianism" means political proposals for land redistribution, specifically the distribution of land from the rich to the poor or landless. This terminology is common in many countries, and originated from the "Lex Sempronia Agraria" or "agrarian laws" of Rome in 133 BC, imposed by Tiberius Gracchus, that seized public land (ager publicus) used by the rich and distributed it to the poor. This definition of agrarianism is commonly known as "agrarian reform." In 18th- and 19th-century England and Ireland, the word identified any land reform movement that sought to redistribute farm lands more equally, especially to landless Irish families.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_ANIMISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Animism is used in the anthropology of religion as a term for the belief system of some indigenous tribal peoples, especially prior to the development of organized religion. Animism encompasses the beliefs that there is no separation between the spiritual and physical (or material) world, and that souls or spirits exist, not only in humans, but also in some other animals, plants, rocks, geographic features such as mountains or rivers, or other entities of the natural environment, including thunder, wind, and shadows. Animism thus rejects Cartesian dualism. Animism may further attribute souls to abstract concepts such as words, true names, or metaphors in mythology. Some members of the non-tribal world also consider themselves animists (such as author Daniel Quinn, sculptor Lawson Oyekan, and many contemporary Pagans).</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_AUTOCRACY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]An autocracy is a system of government in which supreme power is concentrated in the hands of one person, whose decisions are subject to neither external legal restraints nor regularized mechanisms of popular control (except perhaps for the implicit threat of a coup d'état or mass insurrection). Absolute monarchy and dictatorship are the main historical forms of autocracy. In very early times, the term "autocrat" was written in coins as a favorable feature of the ruler, having some connection to the concept of "lack of conflicts of interests".[PARAGRAPH:1]Both totalitarianism and military dictatorship are often identified with, but need not be, an autocracy. Totalitarianism is a system where the state strives to control every aspect of life and civil society. It can be headed by a supreme dictator, making it autocratic, but it can also have a collective leadership such as a commune, junta, or single political party.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CAPITALISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Capitalism is an economic system based on private ownership of the means of production and their operation for profit. Characteristics central to capitalism include private property, capital accumulation, wage labor, voluntary exchange, a price system, and competitive markets. In a capitalist market economy, decision-making and investment is determined by the owners of the factors of production in financial and capital markets, and prices and the distribution of goods are mainly determined by competition in the market. Capitalism has existed under many forms of government, in many different times, places, and cultures. Following the decline of mercantilism, mixed capitalist systems became dominant in the Western world and continue to spread.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CITY_STATES_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A city-state is a sovereign state that consists of a city and its dependent territories. Historically, this included famous cities like Rome, Athens, Carthage, and the Italian city-states during the Renaissance-but today only a handful of sovereign city-states exist, with some disagreement as to which are city-states. However, a great deal of consensus exists that the term properly applies to Singapore, Monaco, and Vatican City. In particular, Singapore has been referred to by The Economist as the "world's only fully-functioning city-state".[PARAGRAPH:1]A number of other states share similar characteristics, and therefore are sometimes also cited as modern city-states. These include Malta, Bahrain, and San Marino which are microstates with high population densities; as well as Qatar, Brunei, and Kuwait, each with an urban center comprising a significant proportion of the population. Notably however, all of them have several distinct settlements and a designated or de facto capital city. Additionally, several non-sovereign cities enjoy a high degree of autonomy, and are sometimes considered city-states. Hong Kong and Macau, along with independent members of the United Arab Emirates, most notably Dubai and Abu Dhabi, are often cited as such.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CONSCRIPTION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Conscription, or drafting, is the compulsory enlistment of people in a national service, most often a military service. Conscription dates back to antiquity and continues in some countries to the present day under various names. The modern system of near-universal national conscription for young men dates to the French Revolution in the 1790s, where it became the basis of a very large and powerful military. Most European nations later copied the system in peacetime, so that men at a certain age would serve 1-8 years on active duty and then transfer to the reserve force.[PARAGRAPH:1]Conscription is controversial for a range of reasons, including conscientious objection to military engagements on religious or philosophical grounds; political objection, for example to service for a disliked government or unpopular war; and ideological objection, for example, to a perceived violation of individual rights. Those conscripted may evade service, sometimes by leaving the country. Some selection systems accommodate these attitudes by providing alternative service outside combat-operations roles or even outside the military, such as Zivildienst (civil service) in Austria and Switzerland. Most post-Soviet countries conscript soldiers not only for Armed Forces but also for paramilitary organizations which are dedicated to police-like domestic only service (Internal Troops) or non-combat rescue duties (Civil Defence Troops) - none of which is considered alternative to the military conscription. As of the early 21st century, many states no longer conscript soldiers, relying instead upon professional militaries with volunteers enlisted to meet the demand for troops. The ability to rely on such an arrangement, however, presupposes some degree of predictability with regard to both war-fighting requirements and the scope of hostilities. Many states that have abolished conscription therefore still reserve the power to resume it during wartime or times of crisis.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CENTRAL_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) is one of the principal intelligence-gathering agencies of the United States federal government. The CIA's headquarters is in Langley, Virginia, a few miles west of Washington, D.C. Its employees operate from U.S. embassies and many other locations around the world. The only independent U.S. intelligence agency, it reports to the Director of National Intelligence. The CIA has three traditional principal activities, which are gathering information about foreign governments, corporations, and individuals; analyzing that information, along with intelligence gathered by other U.S. intelligence agencies, in order to provide national security intelligence assessment to senior United States policymakers; and, upon the request of the President of the United States, carrying out or overseeing covert activities and some tactical operations by its own employees, by members of the U.S. military, or by other partners. It can, for example, exert foreign political influence through its tactical divisions, such as the Special Activities Division. In 2013, the Washington Post reported that the CIA's share of the National Intelligence Program (NIP), a non-military component of the overall U.S. Intelligence Community Budget, has increased to 28% in 2013, exceeding the NIP funding received by military agencies the National Reconnaissance Office (NRO) and the National Security Agency (NSA). The CIA has increasingly taken on offensive roles, including covert paramilitary operations. One of its largest divisions, the Information Operations Center (IOC), has shifted focus from counter-terrorism to offensive cyber-operations. Several CIA activities have attracted criticism. They include nonconsensual human experiments, extraordinary rendition, enhanced interrogation techniques, targeted killings, assassinations and the funding and training of militants who would go on to kill civilians and non-combatants.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_CENTRAL_PLANNING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A planned economy is an economic system in which inputs are based on direct allocation. Economic planning may be carried out in a decentralized, distributed or centralized manner depending on the specific organization of economic institutions. An economy based on economic planning (either through the state, an association of worker cooperatives or another economic entity that has jurisdiction over the means of production) appropriates its resources as needed, so that allocation comes in the form of internal transfers involving the purchasing of assets by one government agency or firm by another. In a traditional model of planning, decision-making would be carried out by workers and consumers on the enterprise-level. Planned economies are held in contrast to unplanned economies, such as the market economy and proposed self-managed economy, where production, distribution, pricing, and investment decisions are made by autonomous firms based upon their individual interests rather than upon a macroeconomic plan. Less extensive forms of planned economies include those that use indicative planning as components of a market-based or mixed economy, in which the state employs "influence, subsidies, grants, and taxes, but does not compel." This latter is sometimes referred to as a "planned market economy". In some instances, the term planned economy has been used to refer to national economic development plans and state-directed investment in market economies.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DIRECT_RULE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Direct Rule is a system where every important order needs to be organized by it's head of state, without or with little help from subordinates and counselors. Direct Rule organization leaves little room for power stuggles, corruption, or democracy, but the amount of work that gets done is limited to the organizational abilities of one person. As such, only very small or very primitive civilizations rely on direct rule.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_DYNASTICISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A dynasty is a sequence of rulers from the same family, usually in the context of a feudal or monarchical system but sometimes also appearing in elective republics. The dynastic family or lineage may be known as a "house"; this may be styled "royal", "princely", "comital", etc. depending upon the chief or present title borne by its members. Historians periodize the histories of many sovereign states, such as Ancient Egypt, the Carolingian Empire and Imperial China, using a framework of successive dynasties. Until the 19th century, it was taken for granted that a legitimate function of a monarch was to aggrandize his dynasty: that is, to increase the territory, wealth, and power of his family members. The longest-surviving dynasty in the world is the Imperial House of Japan, the Yamato dynasty, whose reign is traditionally dated to 660 BC.[PARAGRAPH:1]Dynasties throughout the world have traditionally been reckoned patrilineally, such as under the Frankish Salic law. Succession through a daughter when permitted was considered to establish a new dynasty in her husband's ruling house. However, some states in Africa (Balobedu), determined descent matrilineally, while rulers have at other times adopted the name of their mother's dynasty when coming into her inheritance: examples include the Dutch House of Orange, the Georgian Bagrationi, and Habsburg-Lorraine. The word "dynasty" is sometimes used informally for people who are not rulers but, for example, members of a family with influence and power in other areas, such as a series of successive owners of a major company. It is also extended to unrelated people such as major poets of the same school or various rosters of a single sports team.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_FANATICISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Fanaticism is a belief or behavior involving uncritical zeal or with an obsessive enthusiasm.  The fanatic displays very strict standards and little tolerance for contrary ideas or opinions.[PARAGRAPH:1]Ever since Christianity was established, some of those in authority have sought to expand and control the church, often through the fanatical use of force. Grant Shafer says, "Jesus of Nazareth is best known as a preacher of nonviolence. The start of Christian fanatic rule came with the Roman Emperor Constantine I as Catholicism. Ellens says, "When Christianity came to power in the empire of Constantine, it proceeded almost to viciously repress all non-Christians and all Christians who did not line up with official Orthodox ideology, policy, and practice". An example of Christians who didn't line up with Orthodox ideology is the Donatists, who "refused to accept repentant clergy who had formerly given way to apostasy when persecuted". Fanatic Christian activity, as Catholicism, continued into the Middle Ages with the Crusades.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_EXCLUSIVISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Religious exclusivism is the doctrine or belief that only one particular religion or belief system is true.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Catholic Church teaches that it is the "one true Church", "the universal sacrament of salvation for the human race" and the "true religion". Muslims believe that Islam is the original and primordial faith, or fitrah, that was revealed by Muhammad. Jews believe that the God of Abraham is the one true God. Buddhist religious exclusivism may be seen in the implication that those who do not accept the teachings of the Buddha, such as the Eightfold Path, are destined to repeat the cycle of suffering through endless reincarnations; while those who practice the true way can reach enlightenment.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_SELF_SUFFICIENCY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Self-sufficiency (also called self-containment) is the state of not requiring any aid, support, or interaction, for survival; it is therefore a type of personal or collective autonomy. On a national scale, a totally self-sufficient economy that does not trade with the outside world is called an autarky. The term self-sufficiency is usually applied to varieties of sustainable living in which nothing is consumed outside of what is produced by the self-sufficient individuals. [PARAGRAPH:1]Practices that enable or aid self-sufficiency include autonomous building, permaculture, sustainable agriculture, and renewable energy. The term is also applied to limited forms of self-sufficiency, for example growing one's own food or becoming economically independent of state subsidies.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TOTALITARIANISM_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Totalitarianism is a political system where the state recognizes no limits to its authority and strives to regulate every aspect of public and private life wherever feasible. Totalitarian regimes stay in political power through an all-encompassing propaganda campaign, which is disseminated through the state-controlled mass media, a single party that is often marked by political repression, personality cultism, control over the economy, regulation and restriction of speech, mass surveillance, and widespread use of terror. A distinctive feature of totalitarian governments is an "elaborate ideology, a set of ideas that gives meaning and direction to the whole society."</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_TYRANNY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A tyrant is an absolute ruler unrestrained by law or constitution, or one who has usurped legitimate sovereignty. Often described as a cruel character, a tyrant defends his position by oppressive means, tending to control almost everything in the state. In ancient Greece, tyrants were influential opportunists that came to power by securing the support of different factions of a deme. Plato and Aristotle define a tyrant as "one who rules without law, and uses extreme and cruel tactics-against his own people as well as others". It is defined further in the Encyclopédie as a usurper of sovereign power who makes his subjects the victims of his passions and unjust desires, which he substitutes for laws.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CIVIC_WARRIOR_CODE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In tribal societies engaging in endemic warfare, warriors often form a caste or class of their own. In feudalism, the vassals essentially form a military or warrior class, even if in actual warfare, peasants may be called to fight as well. In some societies, warfare may be so central that the entire people (or, more often, large parts of the male population) may be considered warriors, for example in the Iron Age Germanic tribes and Indian clans like the Rajputs. Many pre-modern states had castes, estates or social groups dedicated to warfare. This includes the Khalsa and Kshatriya castes in ancient and modern India, the samurai class in feudal Japan, the Timawa and Maharlika classes in pre-colonial Philippines and noble knights in feudal Europe.[PARAGRAPH:1]In many societies in which a specialized warrior class exists, specific codes of conduct (ethical code or honour code) are established to ensure that the warrior class is not corrupted or otherwise dangerous to the rest of society. Common features include valuing honour in the forms of faith, loyalty and courage.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CLASSICAL_TEMPLE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In Civilization IV, a temple is defined as a building where the faithful come to worship. Christians call their temples "churches," while Muslims call theirs "mosques," and Jews call theirs, simply, "temples." Temples are far more common than cathedrals, but much less large and ornate. Even the smallest village can possess a temple.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SAN_MARCO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]San Marco Basilica, the cathedral church of Venice, is the most famous of the city's churches and one of the best known examples of Byzantine architecture. It lies on Piazza San Marco adjacent and connected to the Doge's Palace. Originally it was the "chapel" of the Venetian rulers, and not the city's cathedral. Since 1807 it has been the seat of the Patriarch of Venice, archbishop of the Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Venice. For its opulent design, gilded Byzantine mosaics, and its status as a symbol of Venetian wealth and power, from the 11th century on the building was known by the nickname Chiesa d'Oro (Church of gold).[PARAGRAPH:2]The first San Marco's was a temporary building in the Doge's Palace, constructed in 828, when Venetian merchants stole the supposed relics of San Marco the Evangelist from Alexandria. This was replaced by a new church on its present site in 832; from the same century dates the first San Marco's Campanile (bell tower). The new church was burned in a rebellion in 976, rebuilt in 978 and again to form the basis of the present basilica since 1063. The basilica was consecrated in 1094, the same year in which the body of San Marco was supposedly rediscovered in a pillar by Vitale Faliero, doge at the time. The building also incorporates a low tower (now housing San Marco's Treasure), believed by some to have been part of the original Doge's Palace. Within the first half of the 13th century the narthex and the new façade were constructed, most of the mosaics were completed and the domes were covered with higher wooden, lead-covered domes in order to blend in with the Gothic architecture of the redesigned Doge's Palace.</English>
		<German>[TAB]Der Markusdom (italienisch Basilica di San Marco) in Venedig war bis 1797 das zentrale Staatsheiligtum der Republik Venedig und ist seit 1807 die Kathedrale des Patriarchen von Venedig. Er befindet sich am Markusplatz im Stadtsechstel San Marco.[PARAGRAPH:2]Bis zum Untergang der Republik war es erklärte Absicht der venezianischen Regierung durch die Jahrhunderte hindurch, den Sitz des Bischofs möglichst weit entfernt vom Zentrum der Macht zu wissen. San Marco dagegen war die Palastkapelle des Dogen, später Staatskirche Venedigs. Sie wurde erbaut als würdige Ruhestätte für die Gebeine des Evangelisten Markus, des Stadtheiligen Venedigs, der den heiligen Theodor als Stadtpatron ablöste. Der Bischofspalast und der Bischofssitz des Patriarchen von Venedig befanden sich bis zur Säkularisierung in dem abgelegenen Distrikt von San Pietro di Castello.[PARAGRAPH:2]Die erste dem heiligen Markus geweihte Kirche wurde 828 gestiftet und in den Jahren 829 bis 832 anstelle einer Hauskapelle des Dogenpalastes erbaut, um die aus Alexandria durch eine List venezianischer Kaufleute entführten Gebeine des Evangelisten Markus aufzunehmen. 976 fielen Kirche, Dogenpalast und 200 Häuser einer Feuersbrunst zu Opfer. Im selben Jahr begann der Doge Pietro I. Orseolo mit dem Wiederaufbau, der nach mehrmaligen Unterbrechungen erst 1094 beendet war. Die (angeblichen) Gebeine des Hl. Markus wurden durch ein (angebliches) Wunder am 25. Juni 1094 "wiedergefunden". Dieser Tag wurde zum Feiertag Inventio Sancti Marci.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BRANDENBURG_GATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Brandenburg Gate is a former city gate and one of the main symbols of Berlin and Germany. It is located west of the city center at the intersection of Unter den Linden and Ebertstra&#223;e, immediately west of the Pariser Platz. It is the only remaining gate of a series through which one formerly entered Berlin. One block to the north stands the Reichstag. The gate is the monumental entry to Unter den Linden, the renowned boulevard of linden trees which formerly led directly to the city palace of the Prussian monarchs. It was commissioned by King Frederick William II of Prussia as a sign of peace and built by Karl Gotthard Langhans from 1788 to 1791. The Brandenburg Gate was restored from 2000 to 2002 by the Stiftung Denkmalschutz Berlin (Berlin Monument Conservation Foundation). Today, it is considered one of Europe's most famous landmarks.</English>
		<German>[TAB]Das Brandenburger Tor in Berlin steht am Pariser Platz in der Dorotheenstadt im Ortsteil Mitte (Bezirk Mitte). Es wurde in den Jahren von 1788 bis 1791 auf Anweisung des preußischen Königs Friedrich Wilhelm II. von Carl Gotthard Langhans errichtet und ist das bekannteste Wahrzeichen der Stadt. Zugleich ist das Tor ein nationales Symbol, mit dem viele wichtige Ereignisse der Geschichte Berlins, Deutschlands, Europas und der Welt des 20. Jahrhunderts verbunden sind. Der Bau ist dem frühklassizistischen Stil zuzuordnen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Mit dem Bau der Zollmauer der Stadt Berlin wurde 1734 ein Vorgängerbau des heutigen Brandenburger Tores als Stadttor an der Straße nach Brandenburg an der Havel errichtet. Die Toranlage bestand aus Pylonen und beigeordneten Wachhäusern. Im Zuge des Ausbaus der Mauer und ihrer Tore ließ Friedrich Wilhelm II. ab 1788 das Brandenburger Tor neu gestalten, das dem Andenken an den Krieg des kurz zuvor verstorbenen Friedrich II. diente, von dessen Verdiensten auch etwas Glanz auf den Neffen und Nachfolger fallen sollte.[PARAGRAPH:2]Als Architekt wurde Carl Gotthard Langhans beauftragt. Er orientierte sich an dem "Stadttor von Athen", das er aus Stichen von Leroy, Stuart und Revett kannte, die aber die Propyläen der Athener Akropolis abgebildet hatten. Das Eingangstor zur Akropolis war im dorischen Stil des Parthenon gehalten, um eine optische Einheit zu bilden. Das Tor hatte eine breite Mittelöffnung und zwei schmale Seiteneingänge für Fußgänger. Im rechten Winkel dazu standen zwei Seitenflügel. Nach Langhans Planung sollten entsprechend beim Berliner Tor durch den breiten Mittelgang die königlichen Kutschen, daneben die sonstigen Gespanne fahren und außen die Fußgänger gehen. In den Seitenflügeln sollten die Wache und die Akziseeinnehmer untergebracht werden. 1788 wurde das alte Tor abgerissen, eine große Baugrube ausgehoben und fundamentiert. 1789 wurde der Neubau begonnen. Die Baukosten lagen bei 111.000 Talern. Am 6. August 1791 wurde das noch nicht ganz fertige Tor geöffnet.[PARAGRAPH:2]Die 1793 von Johann Gottfried Schadow gefertigte Quadriga auf dem Brandenburger Tor stellte ursprünglich nach der wohl überwiegend vertretenen Auffassung eine geflügelte Friedensbringerin dar. Das Brandenburger Tor erhielt den Namen Friedenstor, diesen Namen zeigte auch eine Inschrift aus Bronzelettern am Tor. Diese Sinngebung interpretiert auch der bildliche Schmuck. Die Entwürfe für die Reliefs wurden vorwiegend von dem Maler und Akademiedirektor Christian Bernhard Rode angefertigt. Schadow hat die Entwürfe überarbeitet und die Steinmetze bei der Ausführung beaufsichtigt. Die Göttin in der Quadriga wird durch das Relief auf der Attika der Stadtseite als Friedensbringerin erklärt. Das Attikarelief steht unter dem Thema "Der Zug der Friedensgöttin". Im Zentrum des Reliefs über dem Mittelgang stehen Sinnbilder auf Frieden und Freundschaft. Die Friedensgöttin Eirene steht auf der äußersten Kante eines Triumphwagens. Mit der Rechten stützt sie sich auf den mit einer Lorbeergirlande geschmückten Rand des Wagens. In der einen Hand hält sie einen Palmenzweig, in der anderen einen Lorbeerkranz. Ihr Wagen wird von vier Eroten gezogen. Weiter rechts auf dem Attikarelief kann man Nike mit Flügeln und Tropaion erkennen.[PARAGRAPH:2]Direkt über diesem Relief steht die Quadriga Schadows. Deren göttliche Wagenlenkerin ist Nike und Eirene in einer Person. Nach einer abweichenden Auffassung soll es sich von Anfang an um eine "Siegesgöttin" gehandelt haben, unter anderem weil davon bereits im Vertrag zur Anfertigung der Figurengruppe vom 22. Juli 1789 die Rede gewesen sei. Schadow hatte ursprünglich für die Wagenlenkerin keine Trophäe entworfen. Ihm schwebte mehr die griechische Eirene als Friedensgöttin vor, als die römische Siegesgöttin Viktoria. 1793 verlangte dann aber ein Akademiebeschluss eine Kopie der Siegestrophäe der Nike rechts auf dem Attikarelief auch für die Wagenlenkerin der Quadriga. Bei der Bevölkerung fand sie keinen Zuspruch. Aufgrund heftiger Kritik besserte Schadow noch ein weiteres Mal nach. Das Tropaion wurde nun durch eine Lanze mit einem Lorbeerkranz und einem römischen Adler ersetzt. Außerdem erhielt die knapp bekleidete Wagenlenkerin nun ein bis auf den Boden reichendes Gewand.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_KGB_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Lubyanka is the popular name for the headquarters of the KGB and affiliated prison on Lubyanka Square in Moscow. It is a large building with a facade of yellow brick, designed by Alexander V. Ivanov in 1897 and augmented by Aleksey Shchusev in 1940-1947.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]The Lubyanka was originally built in 1898 as the Neo-Baroque headquarters of the All-Russia Insurance Company, noted for its beautiful parquet floors and pale green walls. Belying its massiveness, the edifice avoids an impression of heroic scale: isolated Palladian and Baroque details, such as the minute pediments over the corner bays and the central loggia, are lost in an endlessly-repeating classicizing palace facade, where three bands of cornices emphasize the horizontal lines. A clock is centered in the uppermost band of the facade.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]Following the Bolshevik Revolution, the structure was seized by the government for the headquarters of the secret police, then called the Cheka. In Soviet Russian jokes it was referred to as the tallest building in Moscow, since Siberia could be seen from its basement. Another joke referred to the building as "Adult's World" as compared to "Children's World," the name of the popular toy store across the street.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]During the Great Purge, the offices became increasingly cramped due to staff numbers. In 1940, the most famous Soviet architect, Shchusev, was commissioned to double its size by adding another storey and engulfing backstreet buildings. Shchusev's design accentuated Neo-Renaissance detailing, but only the left part of the facade was reconstructed under his direction in the 1940s, due to the war and other hindrances. This asymmetric facade survived intact until 1983, when the symmetry was restored at the urging of Yuri Andropov in accordance with Shchusev's plans.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]Although the Soviet secret police changed its name many times, its headquarters remained in this building. Secret police chiefs from Lavrenty Beria to Yuri Andropov used the same office on the third floor, which looked down on the statue of Cheka founder Felix Dzerzhinsky. A prison at the ground floor of the building figures prominently in Aleksandr Solzhenitsyn's classic study of the Soviet police state, The Gulag Archipelago. Famous inmates held, tortured and interrogated there include Sidney Reilly, Raoul Wallenberg, János Esterházy and Father Walter Ciszek, S.J.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE][TAB]After the dissolution of the KGB, the Lubyanka became the headquarters of the Border Guard Service of Russia, and houses the Lubyanka prison and one directorate of the Federal Security Service of the Russian Federation (FSB). In addition a museum of the KGB was opened to the public. On November 11, 1999 a fire broke out in the Lubyanka. Four FSB agents were injured, but damage was relatively mild. The fire was later traced to faulty wiring.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ISHTAR_GATE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Ishtar Gate was the eighth gate to the inner city of Babylon. It was constructed in about 575 BC by order of King Nebuchadnezzar II on the north side of the city.[PARAGRAPH:2]Dedicated to the Babylonian goddess Ishtar, the gate was constructed of blue glazed tiles with alternating rows of bas-relief sirrush (dragons) and aurochs.[PARAGRAPH:2]The roof and doors of the gate were of cedar, according to the dedication plaque. Through the gate ran the Processional Way, which was lined with walls covered in lions on glazed bricks (about 120 of them).[PARAGRAPH:2]Statues of the deities were paraded through the gate and down the Processional Way each year during the New Year's celebration.[PARAGRAPH:2]Originally the gate, being part of the Walls of Babylon, was considered one of the Seven Wonders of the world until, in the 6th century AD, it was replaced by the Lighthouse of Alexandria.[PARAGRAPH:2]A reconstruction of the Ishtar Gate and Processional Way was built at the Pergamon Museum in Berlin out of material excavated by Robert Koldewey and finished in the 1930s. It includes the inscription plaque. It stands 47 feet high and 100 feet wide (14 meters by 30 meters). The excavation ran from 1902-1914, and, during that time, 45 feet of the foundation of the gate was uncovered.[PARAGRAPH:2]The gate was in fact a double gate. The part that is shown in the Pergamon Museum today is only the smaller, frontal part, while the larger, back part was considered too large to fit into the constraints of the structure of the museum. It is in storage.[PARAGRAPH:2]Parts of the gate and lions from the Processional Way are in various other museums around the world. Only three museums acquired dragons, while lions went to several museums. The Istanbul Archaeology Museum has lions, dragons, and bulls. The Detroit Institute of Arts houses a dragon. The Röhsska Museum in Gothenburg, Sweden, has one dragon and one lion; the Louvre, the State Museum of Egyptian Art in Munich, the Royal Ontario Museum in Toronto, the University of Pennsylvania Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology in Philadelphia, the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York, the Oriental Institute in Chicago, the Rhode Island School of Design Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts in Boston, and the Yale University Art Gallery in New Haven, Connecticut, each have lions.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_CANAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Grand Canal in China, also known as the Beijing-Hangzhou Grand Canal is the longest canal or artificial river in the world. Starting at Beijing, it passes through Tianjin and the provinces of Hebei, Shandong, Jiangsu and Zhejiang to the city of Hangzhou. The oldest parts of the canal date back to the 5th century BC, although the various sections were finally combined during the Sui Dynasty (581-618 CE).[NEWLINE][TAB]The total length of the Grand Canal is 1,776 km (1,103 miles). Its greatest height is reached in the mountains of Shandong, at a summit of 42 m (138 ft). Ships in Chinese canals did not have trouble reaching higher elevations after the pound lock was invented in the 10th century, during the Song Dynasty (960-1279), by the government official and engineer Qiao Weiyo. The canal's size and grandeur won it the admiration of many throughout history, including the Japanese monk Ennin (794-864), the Persian historian Rashid al-Din (1247-1318), the Korean official Choe Bu (1454-1504) and the Italian missionary Matteo Ricci (1552-1610).[NEWLINE][TAB]Historically, periodic flooding of the adjacent Yellow River threatened the safety and functioning of the canal. During wartime the high dikes of the Yellow River were sometimes deliberately broken in order to flood advancing enemy troops. This caused disaster and prolonged economic hardships. Despite temporary periods of desolation and disuse, the Grand Canal furthered an indigenous and growing economic market in China's urban centers through all the ages since the Sui period.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ST_BASIL_CATHEDRAL_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Cathedral of Vasily the Blesseds a church in Red Square in Moscow, Russia. The building, now a museum, is officially known as the Cathedral of the Intercession of the Most Holy Theotokos on the Moat. It was built from 1555-61 on orders from Ivan the Terrible and commemorates the capture of Kazan and Astrakhan. A world-famous landmark, it was the city's tallest building until the completion of the Ivan the Great Bell Tower in 1600. The original building, known as Trinity Church and later Trinity Cathedral, contained eight side churches arranged around the ninth, central church of Intercession; the tenth church was erected in 1588 over the grave of venerated local saint Vasily (Basil). In the 16th and 17th centuries, the church, perceived as the earthly symbol of the Heavenly City, as happens to all churches in Byzantine Christianity, was popularly known as the "Jerusalem" and served as an allegory of the Jerusalem Temple in the annual Palm Sunday parade attended by the Patriarch of Moscow and the tsar.[NEWLINE][TAB]The building is shaped as a flame of a bonfire rising into the sky, a design that has no analogues in Russian architecture. Dmitry Shvidkovsky, in his book Russian Architecture and the West, states that "it is like no other Russian building. Nothing similar can be found in the entire millennium of Byzantine tradition from the fifth to fifteenth century ... a strangeness that astonishes by its unexpectedness, complexity and dazzling interleaving of the manifold details of its design." The cathedral foreshadowed the climax of Russian national architecture in the 17th century.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CHARTERED_COMPANY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A chartered company is an association formed by investors or shareholders for the purpose of trade, exploration, and colonization. Companies enabled merchants to band together to undertake ventures requiring more capital than was available to any one merchant or family. From the sixteenth century onwards, groups of European investors formed companies to underwrite and profit from the exploration of Africa, India, Asia, the Caribbean and North America, usually under the patronage of one state, which issued the company's charter. But chartered companies go back into the medieval period. Authorizations of charters enabled even small states to greatly augment their influence by indirect rule, steering private resources into national pursuits of exploration and trade. As they grew wealthier, some companies developed extensive administrations for their ventures, and frequently conducted local affairs with little homeland oversight.[NEWLINE][TAB]Chartered companies were usually formed, incorporated and legitimised under a royal or, in republics, an equivalent government charter. This document set out the terms under which the company could trade; defined its boundaries of influence, and described its rights and responsibilities.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_CONCEPT_ESPIONAGE_PEDIA_SR</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Espionage[\H1][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Espionage Points[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Using the Espionage Slider, players may assign a percentage of their trade income towards the production of Espionage Points. On the Espionage Screen, these points may be assigned to leaders that the player has met. These points may be used to perform various Active and Passive Espionage Missions. Active Missions require the player to spend Espionage Points and have a spy in the territory of the opponent they wish to perform the mission against. Passive Missions will take effect as the player accrues more points against a specific opponent. Having more espionage points accumulated will increase the cost of your opponents' missions towards you and reduce the cost of your missions towards them.[PARAGRAPH:1]The [LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]Courthouse[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]Jail[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_PALACE]Palace[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_CASTLE]Castle[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_SECURITY]Security Bureau[\LINK] and [LINK=BUILDING_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY]Intelligence Agency[\LINK] all increase the production of Espionage points. The Security Bureau Building increases the point cost of enemy missions in your cities.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Espionage Screen[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Espionage Points may be assigned to specific opponents on the Espionage Screen. If you do not assign points to specific leaders, they will be evenly divided between all known civs. By increasing the "Weight" item next to each opponent's portrait, you can assign the portion you would like each opponent to receive. Increasing the weight next to an opponent's name to "1" will assign all Espionage Points to that opponent. Increasing one opponent's weight to "2" while keeping two other opponents' weight at "1" and another's at "0" will give the first opponent twice as many points as the second and third, while the fourth will receive none. You may assign Weights in any fractions you like, up to 99. In this way, you can finely tune the portion of Espionage Points you would like assigned to each of your opponents.[PARAGRAPH:1]Below "Weight" is a number that shows the cost modifier for your Espionage Missions against this opponent. This number is based on the total number of Espionage Points you have spent throughout the game against this opponent. If the number is below 100%% that means you have spent more on Espionage than your opponent, and your missions may be performed at a discount. If the number is greater than 100%%, it means your opponent has spent more on Espionage than you. This will increase the cost of your Espionage Missions directed towards that opponent. The bottom item on the list states exactly how many Espionage Points you earn per turn towards that opponent. You can also see the Espionage Points you have against all players and the points they have against you by hovering the mouse over their score in the main interface.[PARAGRAPH:1]On the right half of the espionage screen is the list of all the Espionage Missions and their costs. You may click on an opponent's portrait to see a list of all their visible cities and the cost of missions in the selected city. Costs vary according to a number of factors, including the size of the city, its distance from your civilization, and religions present. If the cost of a Mission is blank, this means that the Mission requires more information to determine the exact cost, meaning you must move a spy into enemy territory before the mission cost can be determined. [PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spies[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Spies may be built by a Civilization that has researched [LINK=TECH_ALPHABET]The Alphabet[\LINK]. Spies differ greatly from most units. Completely invisible to enemy Civilizations, Spies can enter enemy territory to perform one Espionage Mission per turn. Active missions are tile sensitive, meaning you will have to sneak your Spy onto the enemy improvement or city you wish to affect. Performing a mission costs a certain number of Espionage Points and will cause an indicator to pop-up for your opponent over the location of the mission, informing him of the act (but not necessarily of your Spy). If the mission succeeds, the Spy may  survive to perform more Missions, or she may be caught and destroyed. If the mission fails, the Spy will be destroyed, but no Espionage Points will be consumed. The cost of these Espionage Missions decrease the longer a Spy remains stationary on a tile, but every turn a Spy remains in enemy territory, there is a chance that she will be caught and destroyed. The chances of being caught increase with your opponent's Espionage spending, with the presence of a Security Bureau and if your Spy has recently performed a mission against that tile. If the Spy is caught, there is also a chance that its owner will be revealed.[PARAGRAPH:1]In addition to performing Espionage Missions, Spies also make excellent intelligence gatherers. They can use enemy roads and enter the cities of opponents with whom the player is at war, allowing the player access to otherwise unreachable information. The downside is that spies have a chance to get caught when they end their turn in unwelcome territory, even if they perform no active missions. Unwelcome territory is any territory belonging to a rival with whom you do not have an open borders agreement.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Missions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]To perform an Espionage Mission, a player must move a Spy unit to the plot or city where they would like to perform the mission and select the Espionage Mission button.[PARAGRAPH:1]The Espionage Missions are:[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Sabotage Improvement[\BOLD] - Destroy an enemy improvement or route[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Sabotage Building[\BOLD] - Destroy a building within an enemy city[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Steal Treasury[\BOLD] - Steal a portion of your opponent's treasury, between 10 and 100%%[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Spread Culture[\BOLD] - Increase your cultural influence in a city[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Poison Water[\BOLD] - Temporarily increase the amount of unhealthiness within an enemy city[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Foment Unhappiness[\BOLD] - Temporarily increase unhappiness within an enemy city[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Support City Revolt[\BOLD] - Send a city into revolt for one turn. This lowers enemy city defense, but does not remove cultural borders[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Steal Technology[\BOLD] - Steal a technology from an opponent[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Sabotage Production[\BOLD] - Destroys all hammers accumulated towards construction in a city[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Sabotage Project[\BOLD] - Destroys an already completed Spaceship Part[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Influence Civics[\BOLD] - Switch one opponent's civic to match a civic you have adopted[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Influence Religion[\BOLD] - Switch an opponent's state religion to your state religion[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Perform Counterespionage[\BOLD] - Temporarily doubles cost of enemy espionage missions[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Passive Missions[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Passive Missions activate automatically as you accumulate certain levels of Espionage Points against an opponent. But as your opponent increases his own cache of Espionage Points, the Point costs of your Passive Missions increase in kind, requiring you to up your own Espionage spending to keep the effects. [PARAGRAPH:1]The Passive Missions are:[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Can See Demographics[\BOLD] - Allows you to see enemy demographics on the Info Screen [F9][NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Can See Research[\BOLD] - Allows you to see what your opponent is researching and how many turns they have until completion[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]City Visibility[\BOLD] - Enemy cities are added to your visibility[NEWLINE][TAB][BOLD]Investigate City[\BOLD] - You may enter enemy city screens by double-clicking on them[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Spy Specialists[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Spy specialists give a bonus to Espionage output and increase the chance of a Great Spy appearing in a city. The [LINK=BUILDING_COURTHOUSE]Courthouse[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_JAIL]Jail[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_INTELLIGENCE_AGENCY]Intelligence Agency[\LINK], [LINK=BUILDING_NATIONAL_SECURITY]Security Bureau[\LINK], and [LINK=BUILDING_KREMLIN]Kremlin[\LINK] World Wonder allow the assignment of Spy specialists in a city.[PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Great Spies[\BOLD][PARAGRAPH:1]Great Spies may occasionally appear in your city through the use of Spy specialists or Espionage-related Wonders. Invisible to all other units, Great Spies can explore rival territory, and will give a massive bonus of Espionage Points against a specific civilization if you expend the Spy in their city. They may also join a city as a super specialist, increasing science and espionage output of a city; or they may construct a [LINK=BUILDING_SCOTLAND_YARD]Scotland Yard[\LINK] in a city, adding a significant bonus to Espionage production in that city.</English>
	</TEXT>	
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_GALLEASS_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Galleass is a large, fast, heavily armed three-masted Mediterranean galley with a forecastle and aftcastle from the 16th and 17th centuries. As converted for military use they were higher and larger than regular ("light") galleys. They had as many as thirty-two oars, each worked by up to 5 men. Much effort was made in Venice to make these galleasses as fast as they could be so they could compete with regular galleys. The gun-deck usually ran over the rowers' heads, although pictures showing the opposite arrangement exist. Galleasses usually carried more sails than true galleys, and were far deadlier; a galley caught broadside lay all but helpless, but coming broadside to a galleass, as with a ship of the line, merely exposed an attacker to her gunfire. The galleass exemplified an intermediate type between the galley and the true man-of-war. Relatively few galleasses were built, one disadvantage was that, being more reliant on sails, their position at the front of the galley line at the start of a battle could not be guaranteed, but they featured at the Battle of Lepanto (7 October 1571), their firepower helping to win victory for the Christian fleet, and some sufficiently seaworthy galleasses accompanied the Spanish Armada in 1588 (e.g. La Girona). In the Mediterranean, with its shallower waters, less dangerous weather and fickle winds, galleasses and galleys alike continued in use, particularly in Venice and Turkey, long after they became regarded as obsolete elsewhere. Later, "round ships" and galleasses were replaced by galleons and ships of the line which originated in northern Europe.</English>
		<German>[TAB]Die Galleasse ist eine große, schnelle und schwer bewaffnete mediterrane Galeere mit drei Masten und je einem schweren Kastell an Bug und Heck, das im 16. und 17. Jahrhundert eingesetzt wurde. Speziell für den militärischen Einsatz gerüstet, waren sie deutlich größer als reguläre Geleeren. Sie war mit um die 32 Ruder ausgerüstet, jedes von 5 Mann gerudert. Die Kanonendecks befanden sich über oder unter den Ruderern. Die Galeassen waren ein Zwischending zwischen Geleeren und späteren schweren Fregatten. Relativ wenige dieser Schiffe wurden gebaut und nach Einsatz in der Spanischen Armada lief der Schiffstyp zusehens aus.</German>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MOTORIZED_INFANTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]In NATO and most other western countries, motorized infantry is infantry that is transported by trucks or other un-protected motor vehicles. It is distinguished from mechanized infantry, which is carried in armoured personnel carriers or infantry fighting vehicles, and from light infantry, which can typically operate autonomously from supporting elements and vehicles for relatively long periods and may be airborne.[NEWLINE][TAB]In Russia and the former Soviet Union, the term motostrelki is used to indicate mechanized infantry; and during the Korean War this usage prevailed in all Warsaw Pact countries.[NEWLINE][TAB]Motorizing infantry is the first stage towards the mechanization of an army. Civilian trucks are readily adaptable to military uses of transporting soldiers, towing guns, and carrying equipment and supplies. This greatly increases the strategic mobility of infantry units, which would otherwise rely on marches or railroads. In practice, armies have found it advantageous to develop trucks to military specifications, such as all-wheel drive, in order to have vehicles that function reliably in extremes of weather and terrain.[NEWLINE][TAB]Motorization provides no direct tactical advantage in small unit combat, because trucks and jeeps are vulnerable to artillery and small arms fire. However, in larger battles, motorized infantry have an advantage in mobility allowing them to move to critical sectors of the battlefield faster, allowing better response to enemy movements, as well as the ability to outmaneuver the enemy.[NEWLINE][TAB]The disadvantage of motorization is that the formation required many vehicles and supplies of fuel to be of advantage.[NEWLINE][TAB]The British created the Experimental Mechanized Force between the wars to test the capabilities of all-arms formations of mechanized units, this included motorized infantry ("Motor Battalions").[NEWLINE][TAB]The speed advantages of motorized infantry first became important in World War II in the German Blitzkrieg. While no more robust than regular infantry moving on foot, its increased speed became decisive in the Blitzkrieg strategy because it could follow the panzer forces and defend its flanks. Notwithstanding the obvious advantages of motorization, most countries only opted for partial motorization of their infantry because of the cost and logistical implications caused by the deployment of so many vehicles.[citation needed]. Even large armies were affected by these factors. The bulk of German and Soviet infantry remained on foot, while U.S. infantry divisions could, if needed, redirect the activities of enough trucks to motorize an infantry regiment. Likewise, infantry divisions of the UK and its Empire could motorize chosen subordinate units, but infantry advanced on foot in most cases.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_MECHANIZED_INFANTRY_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Mechanized infantry are infantry equipped with armored personnel carriers (APCs) or infantry fighting vehicles (IFVs) for transport and combat.[NEWLINE][TAB]Mechanized infantry is distinguished from motorized infantry in that its vehicles provide a degree of protection from hostile fire, as opposed to "soft-skinned" wheeled vehicles (trucks or jeeps) for motorized infantry. Most APCs and IFVs are fully tracked, or are all-wheel drive vehicles (6×6 or 8×8), for mobility across rough ground. Some nations distinguish between mechanized and armoured infantry, designating troops carried by APCs as mechanized and those in IFVs as armoured.[NEWLINE][TAB]The support weapons for mechanized infantry are also provided with motorized transport, or are built directly into combat vehicles, in order to keep pace with the mechanized infantry in combat. For units equipped with most types of APC or any type of IFV, fire support weapons, such as machine guns, autocannons, small-bore direct-fire howitzers, and even anti-tank guided missiles, are often mounted directly on the infantry's own transport vehicles.[NEWLINE][TAB]Compared with "light" truck-mobile infantry, mechanized infantry can maintain rapid tactical movement and (if mounted in IFVs) possess more integral firepower. They require more combat supplies (ammunition and especially fuel) and ordnance supplies (spare vehicle components), and a comparatively larger proportion of their manpower is required to crew and maintain the vehicles. For example, most APCs mount a section of seven or eight infantrymen, but have a crew of two. Most IFVs only carry six or seven infantry, but require a crew of three. To be effective in the field, mechanized units also require large numbers of mechanics with specialized maintenance and recovery vehicles and equipment.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_HORSE_ARCHER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The power of mobility given by mounted units was recognized early on, but was offset by the difficulty of raising large forces and by the inability of horses (then mostly small) to carry heavy armor. Cavalry techniques were an innovation of equestrian nomads of the Central Asian and Iranian steppe and pastoralist tribes such as the Persian Parthians and Sarmatians.[TAB]865 BC, the men had no spurs, saddles, saddle cloths, or stirrups. Fighting from the back of a horse was much more difficult than mere riding. The cavalry acted in pairs; the reins of the mounted archer were controlled by his neighbour's hand. Even at this early time, cavalry used swords, shields, and bows.[TAB]From earliest times cavalry had the advantage of improved mobility, and a man fighting from horseback also had the advantages of greater height, speed, and inertial mass over an opponent on foot. Another element of horse mounted warfare is the psychological impact a mounted soldier can inflict on an opponent.[TAB]The speed, mobility and shock value of the cavalry was greatly appreciated and exploited in armed forces in the Ancient and Middle Ages; some forces were mostly cavalry, particularly in nomadic societies of Asia, notably the Mongol armies.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_LEADER_MEIJI_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[H1]Emperor Meiji [\H1][NEWLINE][BOLD]122nd Emperor of Japan [\BOLD][NEWLINE][BOLD]Lived: [\BOLD] 1852 - 1912[NEWLINE][PARAGRAPH:2][BOLD]Background:[\BOLD][NEWLINE][TAB]Emperor Meiji (November 3, 1852 - July 30, 1912), or Meiji the Great, was the 122nd Emperor of Japan according to the traditional order of succession, reigning from February 3, 1867 until his death on July 30, 1912. He presided over a time of rapid change in the Empire of Japan, as the nation quickly changed from a feudal state to a capitalist and imperial world power, characterized by Japan industrial revolution.[PARAGRAPH:2]At the time of Meiji's birth in 1852, Japan was an isolated, pre-industrial, feudal country dominated by the Tokugawa shogunate and the daimyo, who ruled over the country's more than 250 decentralized domains. By the time of his death in 1912, Japan had undergone a political, social, and industrial revolution at home and emerged as one of the great powers on the world stage. The New York Times summed up this transformation at his funeral in 1912, with the words: "the contrast between that which preceded the funeral car and that which followed it was striking indeed. Before it went old Japan; after it came new Japan."[PARAGRAPH:2]In Japan, the reigning Emperor is always referred to as "The Emperor"; since the modern era, a deceased Emperor is referred to by a posthumous name, which is the name of the era coinciding with the Emperor's reign. Having ruled during the Meiji period, the Emperor is thus, posthumously known as "the Meiji Emperor" or simply "Emperor Meiji". His personal name, which is not used in any formal or official context, was Mutsuhito.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_NAVIGATION_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Sailors navigating in the Mediterranean made use of several techniques to determine their location, including staying in sight of land and understanding of the winds and their tendencies. Minoans of Crete are an example of an early Western civilization that used celestial navigation. Their palaces and mountaintop sanctuaries exhibit architectural features that align with the rising sun on the equinoxes, as well as the rising and setting of particular stars. The Minoans made sea voyages to the island of Thera and to Egypt. Both of these trips would have taken more than a day's sail for the Minoans and would have left them traveling by night across open water. Here the sailors would use the locations of particular stars, especially those of the constellation Ursa Major, to orient the ship in the correct direction.[TAB]Written records of navigation using stars, or celestial navigation, go back to Homer's Odyssey where Calypso tells Odysseus to keep the Bear (Ursa Major) on his left hand side and at the same time to observe the position of the Pleiades, the late-setting Boötes and the Orion as he sailed eastward from her island Ogygia traversing the Ocean. The Greek poet Aratus wrote in his Phainomena in the third century BC detailed positions of the constellations as written by Eudoxos. The positions described do not match the locations of the stars during Aratus' or Eudoxos' time for the Greek mainland, but some argue that they match the sky from Crete during the Bronze Age. This change in the position of the stars is due to the wobble of the Earth on its axis which affects primarily the pole stars. Around 1000 BC the constellation Draco would have been closer to the North Pole than Polaris. The pole stars were used to navigate because they did not disappear below the horizon and could be seen consistently throughout the night.[TAB]By the third century BC the Greeks had begun to use the Little Bear, Ursa Minor, to navigate. In the mid-1st century AD Lucan writes of Pompey who questions a sailor about the use of stars in navigation. The sailor replies with his description of the use of circumpolar stars to navigate by. To navigate along a degree of latitude a sailor would have needed to find a circumpolar star above that degree in the sky. For example, Apollonius would have used ? Draconis to navigate as he traveled west from the mouth of the Alpheus River to Syracuse.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_CRUISER_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A cruiser is a type of warship. The term has been in use for several hundred years, and has had different meanings throughout this period. During the Age of Sail, the term cruising referred to certain kinds of missions - independent scouting, raiding or commerce protection - fulfilled by a frigate or sloop, which were the cruising warships of a fleet. From the middle of the 19th century, cruiser came to be a classification for the ships intended for this kind of role, though cruisers came in a wide variety of sizes, from the small protected cruiser to armored cruisers which were as large (though not as powerful) as a battleship. By the early 20th century, cruisers could be placed on a consistent scale of warship size, smaller than a battleship but larger than a destroyer. In 1922, the Washington Naval Treaty placed a formal limit on cruisers, which were defined as warships of up to 10,000 tons displacement carrying guns no larger than 8 inches in calibre. These limits shaped cruisers up until the end of World War II. The very large battlecruisers of the World War I era were now classified, along with battleships, as capital ships. In the later 20th century, the obsolescence of the battleship left the cruiser as the largest and most powerful surface combatant. The role of the cruiser varied according to ship and navy, often including air defense, commerce raiding and shore bombardment. The U.S. Navy in the Cold War period built guided-missile cruisers primarily designed to provide air defense, while the navy of the USSR built battlecruisers with heavy anti-ship missiles designed to sink NATO carrier task forces.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_TECH_LEATHER_WORKING_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Leather tanning is without a doubt one of the oldest human activities. In the beginning, skins obtained from hunting and livestock breeding could be used for clothing or tents, but they became stiff at low temperatures, while they rotted with heat. It was probably then that attempts were made to render them more flexible and stronger by rubbing in animal fats, the first rudimental tanning process is mentioned in Assyrian texts and in Homers Iliad.[PARAGRAPH:1]Another process was smoking, which almost certainly started by accident, and which later became formaldehyde tanning, as this substance is found in the vapors produced by burning green leaves and branches. It was soon discovered that the rotting process could also be stopped by drying, carried out by exposure to the sun or by the dehydrating action of salt. Vegetable tanning was also known in very ancient times although it is not clear how the tanning action of the tannin contained in the bark of some plants (especially oak) was discovered. Another method known since the earliest times is tanning, based on the use of alum, a mineral which is fairly widespread in nature, particularly in volcanic areas.[PARAGRAPH:1]These methods, which gradually became more refined and efficient, allowed skins to be used in the ancient world and continued to do so for century after century up to the present day.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BIT_DINU_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]The Code of Hammurabi is a well-preserved Babylonian law code of ancient Mesopotamia, dating back to about 1754 BC (Middle Chronology). It is one of the oldest deciphered writings of significant length in the world. The sixth Babylonian king, Hammurabi, enacted the code, and partial copies exist on a seven and a half foot stone stele and various clay tablets. The code consists of 282 laws, with scaled punishments, adjusting "an eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth" (lex talionis) as graded depending on social status, of slave versus free man. Nearly one-half of the code deals with matters of contract, establishing, for example, the wages to be paid to an ox driver or a surgeon. Other provisions set the terms of a transaction, establishing the liability of a builder for a house that collapses, for example, or property that is damaged while left in the care of another. A third of the code addresses issues concerning household and family relationships such as inheritance, divorce, paternity, and sexual behavior. Only one provision appears to impose obligations on an official; this provision establishes that a judge who reaches an incorrect decision is to be fined and removed from the bench permanently. A few provisions address issues related to military service.[PARAGRAPH:1]Much Babylonian legal precedent remained in force, even through the Persian, Greek and Parthian conquests, which had little effect on private life in Babylonia; and it survived to influence Romans. The laws and customs that preceded the Code may be called "early"; that of the Neo-Babylonian empire (as well as the Persian, Greek, etc.), "late". The law of Assyria was derived from the Babylonian, but it conserved early features long after they had disappeared elsewhere.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_UNIT_SLAVE_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]Slavery existed before written history and in many cultures. It was once institutionally recognized by most societies, but has now been outlawed in all recognized countries, the last being Mauritania in 2007. Chattel slavery is still practiced in areas controlled by ISIS. In other areas slavery continues through such practices as debt bondage, serfdom, domestic servants kept in captivity, certain adoptions in which children are forced to work as slaves, child soldiers, human trafficking, and forced marriage.</English>
	</TEXT>
	<TEXT>
		<Tag>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_MISSILE_SILO_PEDIA</Tag>
		<English>[TAB]A missile launch facility, also known as an underground missile silo, launch facility-LF or nuclear silo, is a vertical cylindrical structure constructed underground, for the storage and launching of intercontinental ballistic missiles (ICBMs). The structures typically have the missile some distance below ground, protected by a large "blast door" on top. They are usually connected, physically and/or electronically, to a missile launch control center.</English>
	</TEXT>
</Civ4GameText>